<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: armchair economist | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//blog/categories/armchair-economist/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//"/>
  <updated>2019-02-04T16:40:38-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Richard Stallman's Mistaken Thinking on Copyright]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//richard-stallmans-mistaken-thinking-on-copyright/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//richard-stallmans-mistaken-thinking-on-copyright</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday I had the honor of seeing <a title="Richard Stallman's Home Page" href="http://www.stallman.org/" target="_blank">Richard Stallman</a>, or <a title="Wikipedia: Richard Stallman" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman" target="_blank">rms</a> as he&rsquo;s known in the computer underground, delivering a lecture about copyright in the digital age at UT.</p>

<p>First, a note on his appearance: I was near the back of a 300-person auditorium, but he looked fairly presentable. He has long hair and a ratty beard, but he was dressed in a clean, bright red shirt and slacks. He wore black Velcro shoes which he quickly slid out of. Another interesting visual was his perfectly spherical basketball-sized belly that stretched his shirt tight against his torso. It was truly amazing given his thin arms and legs!</p>

<p>And now onto the intellectual bits&hellip;</p>

<p>Stallman is a big believer in freedom, and he believes that software should be free (as in speech, not as in beer). Rather than referring to price, free software means the user is free to do what they please, namely <a title="Free Software Foundation Definition" href="http://www.fsf.org/about/what-is-free-software" target="_blank">modify and share</a>. Here&rsquo;s the <a title="Free Software" href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html" target="_blank">definition from the horse&rsquo;s mouth</a>:</p>

<blockquote><em>Free software is a matter of the users' freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software.  More precisely, it refers to four kinds of freedom, for the users of the software: </em>

 * <em>The freedom to run the program, for any purpose (freedom 0).</em>
 * <em>The freedom to study how the program works, and adapt it to your needs (freedom 1). Access to the source code is a precondition       for this. </em>
 * <em>The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor (freedom 2). </em>
 * <em>The freedom to improve the program, and release your improvements (and modified versions in general) to the public, so that the whole community benefits (freedom 3). Access to the source code is a precondition for this.</em>

</blockquote>


<p>His ideas are very extreme&mdash;likely galvanized by having to defend his position for 20+ years. I did not appreciate his call to &ldquo;argue the moral high ground&rdquo; which generally means &ldquo;use emotion instead of logic.&rdquo; To be sure, people make decisions based on emotion rather than logic, but his call-to-arms felt flimsy without proper reasoning to back the argument.</p>

<p>Along the emotional lines, he lividly proclaimed that &lsquo;people who attack sharing are attacking society because sharing forms the bonds of society!&rsquo; &ldquo;Sharing is good&rdquo; he said in a moment that made me conjure kindergarten memories. He also evokes the positive nostalgia of browsing your friend&rsquo;s library and borrowing a book. He mocked the idea of borrowing an e-book and, with the e-book, the entire e-reader that it is bound to. These ideas form the basis of his argument that sharing should continue with digital works.</p>

<p>After ruminating on the subject and discussing it with a few peers, I believe that Stallman had the right information but came to the wrong conclusion. The fundamental issue is sharing. Traditionally, sharing involves physical objects that cannot conform to his four freedoms; with physical objects there is only one copy of an item that cannot be easily replicated. He claims that a physical object is its own source code and the user is free to alter it and share the object. This is the first mistake: digital objects have recipes, blueprints, and materials that are the source code. Software today is a standalone product that you pay for&mdash;as with physical objects, the source will cost you.</p>

<p>Stallman&rsquo;s second mistake comes when he equates the digital analog of sharing physical objects into modifying and distributing new copies. Physical objects can be modified and distributed, but the owner gives up the object (for some period of time) whenever they share. As time passes the item changes hands and wears (nicks, folds, scratches, pen marks, etc). If a user wants access to the physical object again, they have to get it back from the borrower or buy a new version. Stallman is not the only person to make this mistake. Currently, there are only two possibilities with digital work:</p>

<ul>
<li>DRM style: one user per purchase &mdash; no possibility of sharing</li>
<li>Napster style: many users per purchase &mdash; sharing is common</li>
</ul>


<p>We need a third method that truly mirrors traditional sharing. This digital system would allow you to share with your friends without retaining a copy for yourself.</p>

<p>Years ago, the music and motion pictures industries (digital media publishers) that are &ldquo;losing sales&rdquo; to piracy should have created a system that allows users to purchase one copy to do with as they please. A simple solution is to create a central web server that contains all available material. Access is then controlled based on holding the license to the material. If a person wants to share or sell media, the user should give up their license and pass it on. We could make the access control very user-friendly, virtually transparent, while providing ubiquitous access and promoting sales.</p>

<p>Sharing is good. We should foster the bonds of sharing. We should not proliferate copying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking of buying a car? Neither is anyone else!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//thinking-of-buying-a-car-neither-is-anyone-else/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//thinking-of-buying-a-car-neither-is-anyone-else</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are <a title="Pictures of cars being stored in random places" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/unsold-cars-around-the-world-2009-2" target="_blank">A LOT of unsold cars worldwide</a>. From the pictures you can understand how every car company, except Subaru, is <a title="Autoblog: 2009 is rough for car companies" href="http://www.autoblog.com/2009/03/03/by-the-numbers-february-2009-wish-it-were-a-leap-year-edition/" target="_blank">hurting financially</a>!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/unsold-cars-around-the-world-2009-2"><img title="Unsold cars, sitting" src="http://static.10gen.com/businessinsider/~~/f?id=49a8645b4b5437fc00b39ad4" alt="Unsold cars, sitting" width="440" height="467" /></a></p>

<p>We are in for a radical shift in the way people buy cars, and the existing excess supply will be worthless. Car companies should drop the unions, sell the backlog off at any price, and embrace the future.</p>

<p>There are a couple great TED talks on the subject:</p>

<ul>
<li><a title="Wikipedia: Larry Burns" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Larry_Burns" target="_blank">Larry Burns</a>, VP of R&amp;D at GM, <a title="TED: Larry Burns" href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/reinventing_the_car.html" target="_blank">talks about the future of cars</a>: sleek, customizable, and powered by hydrogen. Great ideas; let&rsquo;s see if GM can follow through.</li>
<li><a title="Wikipedia: Amory Lovins" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amory_Lovins" target="_blank">Amory Lovins</a>, chairman of the <a title="Wikipedia: Rocky Mountain Institute" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rocky_Mountain_Institute" target="_blank">Rocky Mountain Institute</a>, <a title="Amory Lovins on TED" href="http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/amory_lovins_on_winning_the_oil_endgame.html" target="_blank">proposes a great plan to reduce our dependency on oil</a>, and in doing so, says that vehicles should be smaller, lighter, and stronger.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Let's get tough on Wall Street]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//lets-get-tough-on-wall-street/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//lets-get-tough-on-wall-street</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Maureen Dowd says it nicely in <a title="Disgorge, Wall St Fat Cats" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/02/01/opinion/01dowd.html?_r=1&amp;ex=1391230800" target="_blank">her editorial</a> in the New York Times. If you didn&rsquo;t read the post already, you should. America needs to get upset, take action, and save the proletariat&mdash;not the fat cat. If the big banks fail, the free market will provide and there&rsquo;s no shortage of smart people looking to make banking salaries. These guys <a title="Efficient Market Hypothesis" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Efficient_market_hypothesis" target="_blank">don&rsquo;t know anything special</a>, well not in terms of stock trends at least&mdash;I doubt you know about million dollar bonuses, private jets, and $100+ bottles of wine :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Common Sense Fix for the Economy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//update-common-sense-fix-for-the-economy/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//update-common-sense-fix-for-the-economy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, one <a title="SethHolloway.com: Common Sense Fix" href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/?p=210" target="_blank">common sense fix</a> for the economy was to drop capital gains taxes. Another one I found and really like is <a title="Wired.com Note to President" href="http://blog.wired.com/cars/2008/10/wall-street-bai.html" target="_blank">building infrastructure</a>.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;A report card issued three years ago by the American Society of Civil Engineers <a href="http://www.asce.org/reportcard/2005/index2005.cfm">gives it all a D</a>. The society says we&rsquo;ve got to spend about $1.6 trillion just to bring things up to a B-.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Comments after the article reveal a lot of fiscal conservatism which I normally agree with. However, in my opinion a government should provide defense and infrastructure. The US is behind on health care, education, and technology (broadband Internet and cell phone services to name a couple). In order to maintain our position of power/esteem (I know people worldwide hate USA so I&rsquo;m not sure what word to use, but you know what I mean), we must invest in infrastructure. America is too spread out to develop fully, but we can focus heavily on urban areas.</p>

<p>As a grad student I think we also need to increase research expenditures :)</p>

<p>This proposal is mired in long-standing debates and historical blunders, but I believe investing in infrastructure is a step in the right direction. I strongly believe that with the right systems in place, economic opportunities are infinite. Our odd blend of public and private systems is failing and needs serious reform.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Sense Fix for the Economy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//common-sense-fix-for-the-economy/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//common-sense-fix-for-the-economy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I came across a &ldquo;<a title="Common Sense Fix" href="http://www.daveramsey.com/media/pdf/the_common_sense_fix.pdf" target="_blank">common sense fix</a>&rdquo; for the economy that I found interesting. In particular, I like the idea of removing capital gains taxes:</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Remove the capital gains tax completely. Investors will flood the real estate and stock
market in search of tax-free profits, creating tremendous—and immediate—liquidity in
the markets. Again, this costs the taxpayer nothing.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure that anyone is staying out of the market for fear of paying 15% tax, but it would be simple to waive gains taxes for 2008.</p>

<p>Ramsey also thinks we should stop paying incentives for CEO failures. I agree. Sure enough, Wall Street has already taken the government&rsquo;s money and <a title="Executives are getting $$$" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/business/2008/oct/17/executivesalaries-banking" target="_blank">paid itself hefty bonuses</a> :&lsquo;(</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
