<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: armchair economist | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/armchair-economist/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-15T17:30:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Richard Stallman's Mistaken Thinking on Copyright]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/richard-stallmans-mistaken-thinking-on-copyright/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/richard-stallmans-mistaken-thinking-on-copyright</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday I had the honor of seeing <a title="Richard Stallman's Home Page" href="http://www.stallman.org/" target="_blank">Richard Stallman</a>, or <a title="Wikipedia: Richard Stallman" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Richard_Stallman" target="_blank">rms</a> as he&rsquo;s known in the computer underground, delivering a lecture about copyright in the digital age at UT.</p>

<p>First, a note on his appearance: I was near the back of a 300-person auditorium, but he looked fairly presentable. He has long hair and a ratty beard, but he was dressed in a clean, bright red shirt and slacks. He wore black Velcro shoes which he quickly slid out of. Another interesting visual was his perfectly spherical basketball-sized belly that stretched his shirt tight against his torso. It was truly amazing given his thin arms and legs!</p>

<p>And now onto the intellectual bits&hellip;</p>

<p>Stallman is a big believer in freedom, and he believes that software should be free (as in speech, not as in beer). Rather than referring to price, free software means the user is free to do what they please, namely <a title="Free Software Foundation Definition" href="http://www.fsf.org/about/what-is-free-software" target="_blank">modify and share</a>. Here&rsquo;s the <a title="Free Software" href="http://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.html" target="_blank">definition from the horse&rsquo;s mouth</a>:</p>

<blockquote><em>Free software is a matter of the users' freedom to run, copy, distribute, study, change and improve the software.  More precisely, it refers to four kinds of freedom, for the users of the software: </em>

 * <em>The freedom to run the program, for any purpose (freedom 0).</em>
 * <em>The freedom to study how the program works, and adapt it to your needs (freedom 1). Access to the source code is a precondition       for this. </em>
 * <em>The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help your neighbor (freedom 2). </em>
 * <em>The freedom to improve the program, and release your improvements (and modified versions in general) to the public, so that the whole community benefits (freedom 3). Access to the source code is a precondition for this.</em>

</blockquote>


<p>His ideas are very extreme&ndash;likely galvanized by having to defend his position for 20+ years. I did not appreciate his call to &ldquo;argue the moral high ground&rdquo; which generally means &ldquo;use emotion instead of logic.&rdquo; To be sure, people make decisions based on emotion rather than logic, but his call-to-arms felt flimsy without proper reasoning to back the argument.</p>

<p>Along the emotional lines, he lividly proclaimed that &lsquo;people who attack sharing are attacking society because sharing forms the bonds of society!&rsquo; &ldquo;Sharing is good&rdquo; he said in a moment that made me conjure kindergarten memories. He also evokes the positive nostalgia of browsing your friend&rsquo;s library and borrowing a book. He mocked the idea of borrowing an e-book and, with the e-book, the entire e-reader that it is bound to. These ideas form the basis of his argument that sharing should continue with digital works.</p>

<p>After ruminating on the subject and discussing it with a few peers, I believe that Stallman had the right information but came to the wrong conclusion. The fundamental issue is sharing. Traditionally, sharing involves physical objects that cannot conform to his four freedoms; with physical objects there is only one copy of an item that cannot be easily replicated. He claims that a physical object is its own source code and the user is free to alter it and share the object. This is the first mistake: digital objects have recipes, blueprints, and materials that are the source code. Software today is a standalone product that you pay for&ndash;as with physical objects, the source will cost you.</p>

<p>Stallman&rsquo;s second mistake comes when he equates the digital analog of sharing physical objects into modifying and distributing new copies. Physical objects can be modified and distributed, but the owner gives up the object (for some period of time) whenever they share. As time passes the item changes hands and wears (nicks, folds, scratches, pen marks, etc). If a user wants access to the physical object again, they have to get it back from the borrower or buy a new version. Stallman is not the only person to make this mistake. Currently, there are only two possibilities with digital work:</p>

<ul>
<li>DRM style: one user per purchase &ndash; no possibility of sharing</li>
<li>Napster style: many users per purchase &ndash; sharing is common</li>
</ul>


<p>We need a third method that truly mirrors traditional sharing. This digital system would allow you to share with your friends without retaining a copy for yourself.</p>

<p>Years ago, the music and motion pictures industries (digital media publishers) that are &ldquo;losing sales&rdquo; to piracy should have created a system that allows users to purchase one copy to do with as they please. A simple solution is to create a central web server that contains all available material. Access is then controlled based on holding the license to the material. If a person wants to share or sell media, the user should give up their license and pass it on. We could make the access control very user-friendly, virtually transparent, while providing ubiquitous access and promoting sales.</p>

<p>Sharing is good. We should foster the bonds of sharing. We should not proliferate copying.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Half Price Books]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/half-price-books/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/half-price-books</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s no doubt that I love <a title="official website" href="http://www.halfpricebooks.com/" target="_blank">Half Price Books</a> as much as the next guy: they have a great selection, (relatively) clean store, friendly employees, and convenient locations. However, this wonderful store does not have an inventory system. When you ask the friendly employee in the clean, convenient location if they have the new <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">Dora the Explorer</span> <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">Harry Potter</span> Arnold <span>Schwarzenegger</span> book, they can only tell you where they think it would be located. There&rsquo;s no definitive, &ldquo;Oh, yes! We have that!&rdquo;</p>

<p>The whole situation is odd since books are easier to track than many other physical goods&ndash;they have barcodes and unique identification numbers. As I understand it, all businesses have to take physical inventory periodically. If anyone in the Half Price Books organization knows what they have on hand, why not open the database for use? My guess is that they probably capture a lot of business from people browsing. A couple weeks ago we went in to get one specific book and walked out with five others that we found along the way. It&rsquo;s unclear whether or not we would have bought the other books without the necessary browsing.</p>

<p>Integrating a search feature into the website would also be handy. I understand that companies should stick to what they&rsquo;re good at, and Half Price Books has done well so far; however, opening the inventory system to search would be a straightforward task that would easily put Half Price Books ahead the elite booksellers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing American Health Care]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/fixing-american-health-care/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/fixing-american-health-care</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After watching Sicko I have been more interested in the American health care situation. I don&rsquo;t trust the government to provide high-quality health care coverage. Moore speaks highly of the English system, but a common perk for jobs in the UK (<a title="effects on Brits who choose private health care" href="http://www.thisismoney.co.uk/tax-advice/income-tax/article.html?in_article_id=408244&amp;in_page_id=77" target="_blank">private health care coverage</a>) suggests that the system is less than perfect. Benefits of America&rsquo;s quasi-privatized system are a wash: a person can receive care, but insurance rarely covers the entire cost of operations and medicine. There are a number of other issues at work (governmental regulations, the patent system, market competition, a lack of care for mentally-ill, &hellip;); however, my intent for this post is not to cover any of these complex issues, nor is it to enrage people or debate over the advantages and disadvantages of private health care. Instead, I simply want to share a solution that I find very clever and achievable: <a title="LetWalMartFixUSHealthCare" href="http://articles.moneycentral.msn.com/Investing/JubaksJournal/LetWalMartFixUSHealthCare.aspx" target="_blank">Let Wal-Mart Fix American Health Care</a>.</p>

<p>If they can roll back prices on so many everyday products, they should be able to hardball health care providers and pass the savings on to the consumers. I&rsquo;ll worship the Church of Wal-Mart if it saves me any of the $3,600 a year I pay for health care for my family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
