<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: random | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-15T18:32:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A bit about music theory]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/a-bit-about-music-theory/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/a-bit-about-music-theory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a bit about music theory with respect to guitars for my brother and decided it was worth sharing.</p>

<p>Scales are a series of notes derived with a set pattern. The root note defines the scale. Let me explain further with two scales that only contain the natural notes (no sharps or flats): A minor and C major. A minor and C major are &lsquo;enharmonic&rsquo; meaning they are the same notes;  the difference between the scales is the root note and the pattern that you follow to find the next note. Observe:</p>

<div>
<div>
<blockquote>A minor scale

Notes: A, B, C, D, E, F, G, A

Frets on the E string: 5, 7, 8, 10, 12, 13, 15, 17

Pattern (intervals between notes): root, +2, +1, +2, +2, +1, +2, +2

C major scale

Notes: C, D, E, F, G, A, B, C

Frets on the E string: 8, 10, 12, 13, 15, 17, 19, 20

Pattern (intervals between notes): root, +2, +2, +1, +2, +2, +2, +1</blockquote>
</div>
</div>


<p>You can play a minor scale by picking the root note then applying the minor pattern: root, +2, +1, +2, +2, +1, +2, +2. In the same way, you can play a major scale by picking a root note then applying the major pattern: root, +2, +2, +1, +2, +2, +2, +1. Another example:</p>

<blockquote>A major scale

Notes: A, B, C#, D, E, F#, G#, A

Frets on the E string: 5, 7, 9, 10, 12, 14, 16, 17

Pattern (intervals between notes): root, +2, +2, +1, +2, +2, +2, +1</blockquote>


<p>In music theory terms, the +1 difference is called a &ldquo;half-tone&rdquo; difference and the +2 is termed a &ldquo;whole tone.&rdquo;</p>

<p>If you play notes (mostly) from one scale, you are said to be in that key. For example, if you play notes (mostly) from the E scale, you&rsquo;re in the key of E (major is generally implied&ndash;minor must be stated).</p>

<p>From scales, we can derive chords. Chords are groups of notes. The basic chord is 3 notes: 1 (root), 3, 5 of the scale.</p>

<p>An A minor chord contains the notes A, C, E (1, 3, 5 of the A minor scale).</p>

<p>The C major chord contains C, E, G (1, 3, 5 of the C major scale).</p>

<p>And the A major chord contains A, C#, E (1, 3, 5 of the A major scale).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s a quick, high-level overview of the basis of all music. Now, rock on! \m/</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for more information, there are some great resources online. One that is nicely chunked is <a href="http://www.musictheory.net/lessons">http://www.musictheory.net/lessons</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is the second notice that your car warranty is about to expire...]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/this-is-the-second-notice-that-your-car-warranty-is-about-to-expire/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/this-is-the-second-notice-that-your-car-warranty-is-about-to-expire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past six months I have been getting roughly one call per day from random 800 numbers from all over the country. The voice changes, but the message is always the same: &lsquo;This is the second notice that your car warranty is about to expire.&rsquo;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spoken to other people who are also getting the calls. A friend of mine just bought a car and is receiving these ominous messages which cannot be true.</p>

<p>The worst part is that I&rsquo;m on the <a title="block phone spam" href="https://www.donotcall.gov/" target="_blank">National Do Not Call Registry</a> which should protect me from these unwanted phone calls. Does anyone know of a class action lawsuit against the filth behind these calls? Does anyone know how to file a class action lawsuit&hellip;</p>

<p>Edit: Thanks for pointing out the typo Jason :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I still love technology]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/i-still-love-technology/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/i-still-love-technology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend did not know about Find/Replace in document editors. Instead of replacing all occurrences of a word she was rereading an assignment. I showed her Find/Replace which not only found every occurrence, including some she had missed, the feature also saved her several minutes. As <a title="see the video on YouTube" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nQUfzRF_drc" target="_blank">Kip says</a>, &ldquo;I still love technology! Always and forever.&rdquo;</p>

<p>This random tidbit merely illustrates the benefits of being technical / surrounding yourself with technical people. Work smarter, not harder!</p>

<p>For anyone that does not know, most word processors and text editors (Google Docs, Microsoft Word, Open Office Writer, etc) have a feature that lets you find words and phrases matching your input. You can even replace the words and phrases. This functionality can save hours if you want to alter the style of a document, for example adding two spaces after a period. Find a period followed by a space, replace it with a period followed by two spaces. You can get fancier with <a title="chock full of information about regex" href="http://www.regular-expressions.info/" target="_blank">regular expressions</a>, but this is a start.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
