<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//"/>
  <updated>2021-08-14T13:38:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite reads in 2018]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2018/"/>
    <updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2018</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/10936110">reads from 2018</a>. In 2018 my reading focused a lot on improving myself in order to make me a better husband, father, manager, and all-around person.</p>

<p>Over the years I&rsquo;ve read a lot about management, however, a lot of it is very high level. I read and enjoyed <a href="https://www.radicalcandor.com/">Radical Candor</a> by Kim Scott because it provided an opinionated overview of how to manage like when and how to have career conversations. I found a lot of the suggestions helpful as I officially began my management career.</p>

<p>I finished the available <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Years_of_Lyndon_Johnson">LBJ biographies by Robert A. Caro</a>, which I highly recommend. Between those and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dictator%27s_Handbook">The Dictator&rsquo;s Handbook: Why Bad Behavior is Almost Always Good Politics</a> by Bruce Bueno de Mesquita I had a new framework for interpreting today&rsquo;s political landscape.</p>

<p>On the non-fiction front, I read and enjoyed the <a href="http://nnedi.com/books/binti.html">Binti</a> series and the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/192752-bobiverse">Bobiverse</a> series. Both were quick, thought-provoking sci-fi series.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BJ Fogg's Model for Behavior Change]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//notes-bj-fogg-behavior-change/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//notes-bj-fogg-behavior-change</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Free-form notes from a presentation by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B._J._Fogg">BJ Fogg</a> on <a href="http://www.behaviormodel.org/">behavior change</a>.</p>

<p>Behavior happens when you have <em>motivation</em>, <em>ability</em>, and a <em>prompt</em>.</p>

<h3>To stop a behavior:</h3>

<ul>
<li>reduce motivation</li>
<li>make it harder</li>
<li>remove prompt</li>
</ul>


<h3>To encourage a behavior:</h3>

<ul>
<li>make it easy</li>
<li>build onto existing routine</li>
<li>re-wire your brain (find a way to celebrate)</li>
</ul>


<p>This is a simple process but change is not easy. We should approach behavior change with compassion, playfulness, and iteration.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite reads in 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite reads from 2017.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">Reamde</a> by Neal Stephenson - I have enjoyed every Neal Stephenson book I&rsquo;ve read, and this is no exception. I&rsquo;ve played a lot of online games over the years, so this book hooked me by starting off with a computer virus spread in an online game. It develops nicely from there.</li>
<li><a href="">The Moon is a Harsh Mistress</a> by Robert Heinlein - Truly ahead of its time. This book felt modern with its space travel and artificial intelligence, but it was written in the 1950s!</li>
<li><a href="">Ancillary Justice</a> by Leckie - This book has won a ton of awards so it is not too surprising that it is good. It has some really interesting ideas with AI and consciousness.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Series</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds</a> by Drew Hayes - College kids with super powers. That&rsquo;s a hell of a mashup. I found the three published books very entertaining. The characters were interesting, the scenarios were realistic, and the magic system was well thought out and balanced (which is not easy to do with super powers).</li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">The Path To Power</a> and <a href="">Means of Ascent</a> by Robert Caro - These are the first two books in a long biography series about LBJ, one of America&rsquo;s most interesting presidents. Ryan Holiday recommended these and I see why. Amazing character and great writing make these books easy to read. It helped me feel better about today&rsquo;s political climate.</li>
<li><a href="">Ideal Team Player</a> by Lencioni - Lencioni has carved out a niche with his leadership fables&ndash;basically, business books wrapped in a narrative. I&rsquo;ve read most of his books now and they fit together really nicely. I want to be an ideal team player and this book gave me food for thought.</li>
<li><a href="">Anatomy of Peace</a> by The Arbinger Institute - Another business book wrapped in a narrative. Peace is a great goal, so I was glad to learn more about how we can all overcome conflict and find peace.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read in 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are the books I read in 2017 categorized as fiction or non-fiction. (The list is also available on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2017/48474315">Goodreads</a>.)</p>

<p>The thumbs up/down rating is fast and loose&ndash;don&rsquo;t take it too seriously.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">Reamde</a> by Stephenson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Blood Mirror</a> by Weeks - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Moon is a Harsh Mistress</a> by Heinlein - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Ancillary Justice</a> by Leckie - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Slaughterhouse-Five</a> by Vonnegut - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Norse Mythology</a> by Gaiman - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Age of Myth</a> by Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Arcanum Unbounded</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Shadows for Silence in the Forests of Hell</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Hope of Atlantis</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Eleventh Metal</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Snapshot</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Oathbringer</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians</a> by Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Invisible Man</a> by Ellison - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Leviathan Wakes</a> by Corey - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds: Year 1</a> by Hayes - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds: Year 2</a> by Hayes - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds: Year 3</a> by Hayes - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Alice&rsquo;s Adventuers in Wonderland</a> by Carroll - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Highwayman</a> by Johnson - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">Good Omens</a> by Pratchett and Gaiman - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">Never Deal with a Dragon</a> by Charrette - &#128078;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">The Path To Power</a> by Caro - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Means of Ascent</a> by Caro - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">On Power</a> by Caro - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Story of Human Language</a> by McWhorter - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Ideal Team Player</a> by Lencioni - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Four Obsessions of an Extraordinary Executive</a> by Lencioni - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Anatomy of Peace</a> by The Arbinger Institute - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Swoly Bible</a> by Mazzetti - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">And Then I Thought I Was a Fish</a> by Welch - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Tao Te Ching</a> by Tzu - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Inevitable</a> by Kelly - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Bad Science</a> by Goldacre - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">Bringing Home the Darma</a> by Kornfield - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">The Book of Mastery</a> by Selig - &#128078;</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite reads in 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite reads from 2016.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1RX9aIm">Lord of All Things</a> by Andreas Eschbach - This book had a lot of new-to-me ideas and the sci-fi was integrated nicely into a story I enjoyed. One of the things that stands out is that tradeoffs exist with every choice.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2ixJgRY">Seveneves</a> by Neal Stephenson - Amazing concepts that my mind keeps turning over. I love Neal Stephenson and this is yet another mind-expanding novel from him. This book really hit him as Elon Musk started speaking more publicly about getting off Earth.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in6xFW">Stories of Your Life and Others</a> by Ted Chiang - I don&rsquo;t tend to read many short stories, but I&rsquo;m glad I read this collection. About half the stories were really good and still have me thinking.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Series</h4>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1YefYmk">Red Rising by Pierce Brown</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1UHiSBW">Riyria Chronicles by Michael J. Sullivan</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iWcyur">Lightbringer series by Brent Weeks</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/294eAPo">Them: Adventures with Extremists</a> by Jon Ronson - A great story in the midst of a very extreme 2016.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHFvrV">Surely You&rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman!: Adventures of a Curious Character</a> by Richard Feynman - This is my new standard for an autobiography. Entertaining and interesting throughout, with great insights into this curious character. I particularly liked that he didn&rsquo;t want more money because it would allow him to afford mistress, which he knew would ruin his life.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iUcmre">Home Game: An Accidental Guide to Fatherhood</a> by Michael Lewis - I would recommend this to any new father. It&rsquo;s short and funny with Michael Lewis plainly saying so many things I had thought. I&rsquo;ve used his question &ldquo;what percentage of the parenting does each parent do?&rdquo; several times now. He says that fathers do much less than mothers but there&rsquo;s a lot of social stigma to admitting that, which made me feel better.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in8Et5">When Things Fall Apart: Heart Advice for Difficult Times</a> by Pema Chodron - This book dovetailed nicely with my efforts to control my emotions. I read no more than one chapter at a time because it&rsquo;s heavy, introspective stuff. I was thrilled that I read this beeok when I saw Derek Sivers mention Pema Chodron in his <a href="http://nownownow.com/about">about now pages post</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>That&rsquo;s my not-so-short list of favorites from 2016. I hope 2017 will be filled with as many great stories.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW 2016 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//sxsw-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//sxsw-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SXSW 2016 was great! I&rsquo;m enjoying the conference more every year. I think last year&rsquo;s presentations were more thought-provoking, but there were several good talks this year too.</p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP90088">Invisible Influence and Winning at SXSW 2016</a> - Contagious was <a href="http://sethholloway.com/favorite-books-read-2015/">one of my favorite books of 2015</a> so I was excited for his keynote. It was good. He played a clip from his appearance on <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2078690/">Brain Games</a> where the show manipulated people into waiting in line for nothing. That idea reminds me a lot of <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/derek_sivers_how_to_start_a_movement">Derek Sivers talk on how to start a movement</a> (which is awesome).</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP93149">President Barack Obama Keynote Conversation</a> - Super cool that Obama was at South by. I really like the POTUS connecting with the people (as opposed to the standard, stuffy keep-the-voters-at-arm&rsquo;s length).</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP91541">Google Self-Driving Car Project</a> - So cool. Last year&rsquo;s Moon Shots presentation by Dr. Astro Teller left me all warm and fuzzy about Google X, and this talk did too. I loved seeing the computer representation next to the camera version. The future is now. (I can&rsquo;t wait for self-driving cars.)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP46272">NativeScript: The Future of Mobile App Development</a> - Wanna write a single JavaScript program that can run on iOS, Android, and Windows phone? Then NativeScript is for you! It&rsquo;s a neat idea, and I think the fact that we keep seeing write-once-run-on-any-native-platform projects shows how valuable such a project would be.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP92018">The Future of Media Companies</a> - Hard to believe that a BuzzFeed speech would have a click-bait title, right?!</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP92035">Daring Greatly</a> - To summarize: breathe. I&rsquo;m being flippant. Brene Brown is amazing and her keynote was no exception. One of my favorites.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP91923">Unstoppable Trends that are Changing the World</a> - Max, the co-founder and CTO of PayPal, is staggeringly smart. The presentation was good. The Q&amp;A was great. In the time it took to read a question, Max could come up with a brilliant, self-assured response that was delivered with precision. He invoked the idea of a shrewd, genius VC.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP48870">The Linguistic Secrets Found in Billions of Emoji</a> - I thought I could buy some nerd-cred with my wife with this one. I don&rsquo;t use emoji like most people use emoji :-\</li>
</ul>


<h2>Monday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP51950">Comments Are Terrible: But They Don&rsquo;t Have to Be</a> - My favorite insight was that the architecture of comment sections can change behavior; for example, a three-column comment section containing <code>for</code>, <code>against</code>, and <code>questions</code> increased civility.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP58524">Bad Robot, Epic Digital, and Google Present Moon Shot. The story of the Google Lunar XPRIZE</a> - JJ Abrams introduced a series of shows chronicling a few teams going for the Google Lunar X prize. Great videos! I love how space is cool now.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_OE05413">Silent Room by Simon Heijdens</a> - Anechoic chamber. Whoa. I only got a minute inside but it was a really neat experience.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tuesday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP52737">The New Battle Over Encryption and How to Survive It</a> - Moxie Marlinspike is amazing. I don&rsquo;t know how someone so humble and idealistic has gained the spotlight, but I&rsquo;m so glad he has. I&rsquo;d rather listen to him than the standard pundit any day.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP57527">Cracking the Code to Your Unlimited Epic Potential</a> - To summarize: breathe.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP90100">Why Happiness Is Hard and How to Make It Easier</a> - To summarize: breathe.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP46758">The Secrets of Machine Learning Revealed</a> - A great summary of machine learning. I really liked how Dr. Domingos distilled the information stating the five schools of ML and their goals.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP57474">Closing Remarks: Bruce Sterling</a> - A SXSW tradition. This year&rsquo;s message seemed to be, &ldquo;by this time next year, Trump will be president, but the U.S. will survive.&rdquo; Bruce is an engaging, entertaining speaker full of energy and ideas.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android vs iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//thoughts-on-android-and-ios/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//thoughts-on-android-and-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I work on Android and iOS I&rsquo;m refining my opinions. Below are my current thoughts about the two ecosystems and underlying languages.</p>

<h2>Objective C vs Java</h2>

<p>Note: I haven&rsquo;t used Swift enough to fairly compare Swift to Objective C. The presence of Swift calls into question the future of Objective C; however, I think Swift eliminates a lot of my gripes with Objective C.</p>

<h3>Objective C wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>Apple docs are generally more pleasant than JavaDocs.</li>
<li>You can pass messages to <code>nil</code> without a <code>NullPointerException</code>.</li>
<li><code>nil</code> is <code>false</code>, which fits how I generally think about problems and saves some typing (<code>if (foo)</code> is not as explicit but explicit null checks are noisy and easily forgotten).</li>
<li>Method names can be more expressive: <code>stringWithCString:inputString encoding:inputEncoding</code> is more clear to me than <code>String(String inputString, String encoding)</code>, which, in practice, is often more like <code>String(String s, String e)</code>. As the signature expands the problem becomes more pronounced. Objective C essentially forces named arguments.</li>
<li>Drama surrounding Java&rsquo;s future under Oracle; for example, Android Dalvik is definitely not Java <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalvik_(software)#Licensing_and_patents"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalvik_">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalvik_</a>(software)#Licensing_and_patents</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Java wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>In wide use outside mobile development, so Java is well known and understood</li>
<li>Simpler memory management, which decreases the amount of syntax and leads to fewer bugs. This combined with the fact that Java is more widely used means that people can more easily ramp up on Android.</li>
</ul>


<h2>iOS vs Android</h2>

<h3>Android wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>Easy and inexpensive (a one-time $25 fee) to create and publish apps.</li>
<li>Registering to open URLs. In Android an app can register to open specific links, like <code>https://youtube.com</code> or <code>seth://foo</code>. This improves the user experience by operating on the link in the best app: if you have the YouTube app, open the video in the app, otherwise fall back to the default browser. iOS achieves a similar effect but cannot register for <code>https://</code> schemes. In practice it works well enough, but custom schemes aren’t as ubiquitous as HTTP(S).</li>
<li>Strings and localization. Android forces you to use a message catalog, which has several advantages: (1) it’s better for reuse; (2) it makes it easier to refactor; (3) it centralizes text so docs and translators can engage more easily; (4) the toolchain is more stable&ndash;Xcode crashes a lot when working with localization and it doesn’t update text changes made through interface builder</li>
</ul>


<h3>iOS wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>One true way to do most things. iOS is pretty strict, but it&rsquo;s easier to find the proper way to do things and leads to greater consistency.</li>
<li>More stable platform.</li>
<li>Higher quality apps and community, on average. While Apple&rsquo;s approval process is a pain and their developer program fees are steep (compared to Android&rsquo;s $0 cost), this probably leads to higher quality.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes from Medical School for Everyone]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//notes-from-grand-rounds/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//notes-from-grand-rounds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/medical-school-for-everyone-grand-rounds-cases.html">Medical School for Everyone: Grand Rounds Cases (Great Courses) by Roy
Benaroch, M.D.</a></p>

<ul>
<li><p>Diseases like Down&rsquo;s syndrome and Ménière&rsquo;s disease are shifting to
drop the possessive noun, so you might hear Down syndrome, Ménière disease,
Alzheimer disease, etc.</p></li>
<li><p>Doctors listen to symptoms then make a &ldquo;differential diagnosis&rdquo;, which
is essentially a working theory. They then test the theory to confirm
the diagnosis. (A &ldquo;differential diagnosis&rdquo; differentiates one particular
disease from other diseases that present similar symptoms; e.g., &ldquo;it
could be brain cancer or a stroke&ndash;differential diagnosis is stroke.&rdquo;)</p></li>
<li><p>Doctors should start with the most specific symptoms. For example,
&ldquo;stomach ache&rdquo; could be caused by hundreds of conditions while &ldquo;a large
lump in my abdomen&rdquo; has fewer causes.</p></li>
<li><p>Modern CPR recommendations are to lay the patient flat and begin
aggressive chest compressions&ndash;no rescue breaths&ndash;while getting others
to call 911 and seek an automated external defibrillator (AED). AEDs are
becoming more common. They instruct laypeople how to proceed and
administer shocks as needed.</p></li>
<li><p>Unexplained weight loss means your body is not absorbing nutrients
properly or is burning calories in an unexplained way. Diabetes and
cancer are common causes.</p></li>
<li><p>Don&rsquo;t assume that your doctors are communicating. Make sure that records
are shared between them and that they know about one another.</p></li>
<li><p>In emergency situations doctors use their A, B, Cs: Airway, Breathing,
Circulation, Disability, Exposure. These are handled in sequence. The
technique is meant to make a complex problem more tractable. If a
patient has a blocked airway, they first intubate (or whatever is
appropriate); if airway is clear they ensure the patient is breathing,
then that the patient&rsquo;s heart is working and the patient is not losing
blood. Disability assesses the patient&rsquo;s general competency, usually
using the AVPU method, where the patient is graded as alert (A), voice
responsive (V), pain responsive (P), or unresponsive (U). This is an
alternative to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glasgow_Coma_Scale">Glasgow Coma
Scale</a>, which uses six
levels of eye, verbal, and motor (EVM) responses. Exposure is about a
more general physical exam, looking for signs of trauma.</p></li>
<li><p>They think King Tut died of sickle-cell disease (a.k.a. sickle-cell
anemia). Sickle-cell carriers are resistant to malaria, so it&rsquo;s a great
trait to have in places where malaria is a leading cause of death;
however, sickle-cell is more likely to kill so the benefits are lost if
a child inherits. (Sickle-cell is inherited in an autosomal recessive
pattern where two carrier parents have a &frac14; chance for the child to be
unaffected, 2/4 chance for the child to be a carrier, and &frac14; chance for
the child to have sickle-cell.)</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read in 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are the books I read in 2016 categorized as fiction or non-fiction. (The list is also available on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2016/48474315">Goodreads</a>.)</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve gone with a thumbs up/down rating to force myself to have an opinion because I&rsquo;m generally positive about any book I read and that&rsquo;s boring.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1SzeEGx">Candide</a> by Voltaire - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1Sa95Od">Infinity Blade: Awakening</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1UHiZNU">Firefight (The Reckoners, book 2)</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1TzQb8P">Calamity (The Reckoners, book 3)</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1TrsifW">Shadows for Silence in the Forests of Hell</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1ORq1y6">Sixth of the Dusk</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1TzQeRQ">Perfect State</a> by Brandon Sanderson -</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1Yeg51d">Warbreaker</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iTmrVs">Legion</a> by Brandon Sanderson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1UHiSBW">The Crown Tower (The Riyria Chronicles, book 1)</a> by Michael J. Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1Yegi4w">The Rose and the Thorn (The Riyria Chronicles, book 2)</a> by Michael J. Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1SzeoaJ">The Death of Dulgath (The Riyria Chronicles, book 3)</a> by Michael J. Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1MchPHv">Theft of Swords (The Riyria Revelations, book 1)</a> by Michael J. Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1Sa8MDd">Rise of Empire (The Riyria Revelations, book 2)</a> by Michael J. Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1Szej6G">Heir of Novron (The Riyria Revelations, book 3)</a> by Michael J. Sullivan - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/22b3BIP">Library at Mount Char</a> by Scott Hawkins - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1Sze2ka">The Naked Sun</a> by Isaac Asimov - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1RX9aIm">Lord of All Things</a> by Andreas Eschbach - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1YefYmk">Red Rising</a> by Pierce Brown - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1MchjJL">Golden Son</a> by Pierce Brown - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1MchjJL">Morning Star</a> by Pierce Brown - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1TcbVD1">The Graveyard Book</a> by Neil Gaiman - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1rq5TbV">The Wizard of Earthsea</a> by Ursula K. Le Guin - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1qBNHuS">The Fifth Season</a> by N. K. Jemisin - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2979vHq">Three Body Problem</a> by Cixin Liu - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/29a9JhV">The Very First Damned Thing</a> by Jodi Taylor - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/29cor9x">Imajica</a> by Clive Barker - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/23R4Rlh">Son of the Black Sword</a> by Larry Correia - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/29veZML">The Adventures of Tom Stranger, Interdimensional Insurance Agent</a> by Larry Correia - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iwQ02B">Night Circus</a> by Erin Morgenstern - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHHSuS">The Children of Hurin</a> by J. R. R. Tolkien - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in1Z2b">The Alchemist</a> by Paolo Coelho - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHQDqu">The Dark Tower I: The Gunslinger</a> by Stephen King - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in6xFW">Stories of Your Life and Others</a> by Ted Chiang - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHGl8a">The Cinder Spires: The Aeronaut&rsquo;s Windlass</a> by Jim Butcher - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iWcyur">The Black Prism (Lightbringer Book 1)</a> by Brent Weeks - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHGMRr">The Blinding Knife (Lightbringer Book 2)</a> by Brent Weeks - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2isVlFw">The Broken Eye (Lightbringer Book 3)</a> by Brent Weeks - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2inhV4G">Six of Crows</a> by Leigh Bardugo - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in8X7e">Oberon&rsquo;s Meaty Mysteries: The Purloined Poodle</a> by Kevin Hearne - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2ixJgRY">Seveneves</a> by Neal Stephenson - &#128077;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/22b3rBi">If You&rsquo;re Not First You&rsquo;re Last</a> by Grant Cardone - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1TCpyOV">The 21 Irrefutable Laws of Leadership</a> by John C. Maxwell - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/29jLAWP">Mindset: The New Psychology of Success</a> by Carol Dweck - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/294eAPo">Them: Adventures with Extremists</a> by Jon Ronson - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hH1HTa">Love Yourself Like Your Life Depends on It</a> by Kamal Ravikant - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iEich0">The 48 Laws of Power</a> by Robert Green - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iTn55d">The Preemie Primer</a> by Jennifer Gunter - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iW7Ooi">You Are a Badass: How to Stop Doubting Your Greatness and Start Living an Awesome Life</a> by Jen Sincero - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHUm7B">Joy on Demand: The Art of Discovering the Happiness Within</a> by Chade-Meng Tan - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHFvrV">Surely You&rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman!: Adventures of a Curious Character</a> by Richard Feynman - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHIhgX">MONEY Master the Game</a> by Anthony Robbins - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in7des">Bull&rsquo;s Eye: The Power of Focus</a> by Brian Tracy - &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iUcmre">Home Game: An Accidental Guide to Fatherhood</a> by Michael Lewis - &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in8Et5">When Things Fall Apart: Heart Advice for Difficult Times</a> by Pema Chodron - &#128077;</li>
</ul>


<p>Want to squeeze in a few more books per year? I read a fair amount of physical and ebooks, but I rely on audiobooks to double my monthly reading. I use and love <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Audible-Free-Trial-Digital-Membership/dp/B00NB86OYE/?ref_=assoc_tag_ph_1422899139880&amp;_encoding=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;linkCode=pf4&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=DYWVSK5ZUM3CXNRC">Audible</a>. Email me if you want me to send you a book from my list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite reads in 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Different books give me different things, so it&rsquo;s hard to rank them. But here are a few books that stand out from this year&rsquo;s reading list.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The Stormlight Archive books 1 and 2 by Brandon Sanderson: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Way-Kings-Stormlight-Archive-Book-ebook/dp/B003P2WO5E/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818313&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Way of Kings</a> and <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Words-Radiance-Stormlight-Archive-Book-ebook/dp/B00DA6YEKS/ref=sr_1_2?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818313&amp;sr=1-2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Words of Radiance</a>. I read seven Brandon Sanderson books in 2015, so it&rsquo;s fair to say I enjoy his writing. This is set to be a 10-book epic fantasy series in the vein of <em>The Wheel of Time</em>, which Sanderson finished with aplomb. I hate having to wait so long to reach the conclusion, but I&rsquo;m prepared to do so because the first two were so good.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Trust-Me-Lying-Confessions-Manipulator-ebook/dp/B0074VTHH0/?tag=theven01-20">Trust Me, I&rsquo;m Lying by Ryan Holiday</a>. The media is bullshit&ndash;read this book if you don&rsquo;t believe me. Ryan Holiday talks candidly about the tricks he and so many others use to generate traffic.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/So-Youve-Been-Publicly-Shamed-ebook/dp/B00L9B7IRC/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818288&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">So You&rsquo;ve Been Publicly Shamed by Jon Ronson</a>. Between this and <em>Trust Me, I&rsquo;m Lying</em> I was really sad about the state of media and the rise of outrage porn. Real lives are ruined and only the media wins.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Art-Asking-Learned-Worrying-People-ebook/dp/B00IRISKD6/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818262&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Art of Asking by Amanda Palmer</a>. Another book with ties to shame and acceptance. Amanda Palmer has a confessional style that is really disarming. People have been really mean to her, so her message of love and empathy is that much more amazing.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Radical-Acceptance-Tara-Brach-ebook/dp/B000FC2NHG/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818241&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">Radical Acceptance by Tara Brach</a>. A breath of fresh air among the negativity in some of my other notable reads from the year. Reading this book made me feel better about myself.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Contagious-Things-Catch-Jonah-Berger-ebook/dp/B008J4GQKW/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817798&amp;tag=theven01-20">Contagious by Jonah Berger</a>. Contagious sheds light on why some things are shared and others aren&rsquo;t, which was particularly interesting in the context of shame and media manipulation.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Things-Shout-Out-Loud-Parties-ebook/dp/B00L2FG1SM/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817769&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">Things to shout out loud at parties. by Markus Almond</a>. I love the style of this book. It&rsquo;s a collection of no-more-than-one-page stories and thoughts so it&rsquo;s very approachable. I think everyone should aim to write a similar book.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Jesus-Son-Stories-Denis-Johnson-ebook/dp/B006JR7XLC/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817738&amp;tag=theven01-20">Jesus&#8217; Son by Denis Johnson</a>. Another book with a unique style. This one is a collection of stories about a junkie stumbling through life where the writing is as stark and jumpy as you&rsquo;d expect from a junkie.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Becoming-Technical-Leader-Gerald-Weinberg-ebook/dp/B004J4VV3I/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817692&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">Becoming a Technical Leader by Gerald Weinberg</a>. This book is unlike any other &lsquo;how to be a leader&rsquo; book that I&rsquo;ve read. It&rsquo;s full of great ideas like, &lsquo;maybe poor personal hygiene is about poor self-confidence so be mindful when offering advice&rsquo; and Satir&rsquo;s interaction model. I highly recommend it for anyone who is becoming a technical leader.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Project-DevOps-Helping-Business-ebook/dp/B00AZRBLHO/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=1450816934&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Phoenix Project by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, and George Spafford</a>. A modern version of <em>The Goal</em>, which helped reinforce past learnings about project management and software deployments.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>I hope 2015 treated you well! I look forward to a similarly stimulating 2016.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Checklist for Success]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//daily-rituals-for-success/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//daily-rituals-for-success</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Personal rituals are fascinating to me. I&rsquo;ve encountered them repeatedly in books, blogs, podcasts, and conversations. They&rsquo;re generally boiled down to 1-60 minute morning rituals, but I chafe at the idea of an immutable hour-long routine because I have at least four different types of days (calm weekday, rushed weekday, calm weekend, and rushed weekend). It&rsquo;s easier for me to think of the idealized morning routine as a daily checklist that I can achieve in whatever order during any waking period.</p>

<p>This year I&rsquo;ve focused a lot on my own health and happiness, paying special attention to what drains me of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7LnBvuzjpr4">my energy</a>. Through reading and experimenting I&rsquo;ve come up with my own checklist. These are the things that I shoot for every day (in no particular order):</p>

<ul>
<li>smile for one minute - Smiling feels good, and there&rsquo;s always something worth smiling about. But I rarely smile. I&rsquo;m generally happy, but I tend to suppress the physical representation of my emotions so I don&rsquo;t smile nearly as much as I&rsquo;d like to. I&rsquo;m working on making my outside match my inside more often.</li>
<li>journal 3+ things I&rsquo;m grateful for - I try to smile while thinking of things I&rsquo;m grateful for. It would be easy enough to say, &ldquo;my wife&rdquo;, &ldquo;my health&rdquo;, and &ldquo;my job&rdquo;, but I try to get more specific. Practicing gratitude has been very helpful for me.</li>
<li>journal anything I&rsquo;m proud of myself for - I struggle with self-confidence and self-compassion, so this running log of goodness helps me feel better.</li>
<li>breathe from the diagram, trying to take only 4-6 breaths in one minute - It&rsquo;s amazing how calm I feel after slowing my breathing&ndash;it&rsquo;s like telling your body, &ldquo;relax&rdquo; and having your body listen.</li>
<li>sleep 7.5+ hours - Sleep is generally the first thing to go when I get busy; however, I&rsquo;m finding that sleep really sets the stage for the day, so I&rsquo;m trying to sleep more.</li>
<li>stand 2+ hours - On my laziest day I could stand for less than five minutes, which is bad for my mood and my metabolism. I installed a flip-up table so I can work standing up. I&rsquo;m trying to stand once an hour (drinking a lot of water helps motivate me). I&rsquo;ve also been doing a lot of housework recently, so I&rsquo;m standing more.</li>
<li>walk at least 3,000 steps - You know that laziest day where I hardly stand? I definitely don&rsquo;t walk much those days. For reference 3,000 steps is roughly 1.5 miles and 30 minutes moving around. Since I made 3,000 steps a goal I&rsquo;ve been able to do it almost every day.</li>
<li>exercise until sweating - Typical exercise guidelines recommend around five hours of exercise per week, but most Americans are barely getting two hours, so I try to be realistic. I think &ldquo;until sweating&rdquo; is a better goal than any specific time. Get the blood moving and enjoy.</li>
<li>have sex - I never see this in people&rsquo;s daily routines, but I think it&rsquo;s very important so I had to include it. That said, this is probably my most skipped routine.</li>
<li>get some physical contact with loved ones (including pets) - Positive physical contact releases oxytocin, which makes us feel connected and warm. Blood pressure drops and we feel a sense of well-being. Pretty powerful stuff. I&rsquo;ve read various studies saying it takes from one second to two minutes, so I shoot for one good purposeful spouse-hug and a minute of cuddling with the pets.</li>
<li>take a probiotic - Get your shit straight. For real.</li>
<li>eat some fiber - See above.</li>
<li>fill in vitamins and minerals you have missed or will miss from your food and drink - I generally eat well for 3/5 feedings (traditional meals plus snacks), but I still miss a lot of nutrients. Vitamin D, which is usually provided by exposure to the sun, is chronically low among programmers. If I can&rsquo;t go for a little walk in the sun then I take my vitamin D.</li>
<li>drink 64+ oz of water - Studies refute the biological need for 8 cups of water, but I&rsquo;ve found that it&rsquo;s fairly easy and it makes me feel better.</li>
<li>brush your teeth twice - Your mother will be proud.</li>
<li>make your bed - For me, this helps set the stage for a productive day. I don&rsquo;t do anything fancy&ndash;just straighten the sheets and comforter and pull them up over my pillows.</li>
<li>stretch - My flexibility sucks. I think some of my body aches come from poor flexibility, so I&rsquo;m working to improve my general mobility.</li>
<li>communicate with someone important to me (preferably someone that I don&rsquo;t work or live with) - Relationships mean a lot to me, yet I&rsquo;m historically bad at keeping in touch. While far from perfect now, by focusing on it every day I&rsquo;ve been able to keep up with more loved ones.</li>
<li>meditate - I try to meditate every day, but &ldquo;meditation&rdquo; is a really open-ended idea. I&rsquo;ve found success in short mindfulness breaks. Focusing on breathing from my diaphragm, clearing my mind with intense exercise, and recognizing the blessings around me all achieve a similar effect for me.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you&rsquo;re on the fence about any item, run the experiment and see how you feel after trying it.</p>

<p>So, what&rsquo;s your daily checklist? What works for you? What percentage of your tasks do you normally complete?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DEFCON 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//defcon-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//defcon-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DEFCON 23 was my favorite DEFCON experience so far. There were a lot of great talks and fun after-hours events. Below is
a list of talks that I attended, for posterity&rsquo;s sake.</p>

<h2>Thursday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Reed">Hardware and Trust Security: Explain it like I’m 5 - Teddy Reed and Nick
Anderson</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Szakaly">Shall We Play a Game? - Tamas Szakaly</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Drake">Stagefright: Scary Code in the Heart of Android - Joshua J.
Drake</a>. This talk explained the Android exploits that
arise because Android pre-processes incoming messages. For example, texting a malicious image leads Android to retrieve
and load the payload before the user even sees a notification. This should make the user interface feel faster, but it
comes at a price.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Schneier">Bruce Schneier Q&amp;A - Bruce Schneier</a>. I &lt;3 Bruce.
He&rsquo;s just so clear and intelligent. I hope we make him head of cyber security for the U.S.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Kamkar">Drive It Like You Hacked It: New Attacks and Tools to Wirelessly Steal Cars - Samy
Kamkar</a>. Samy is one of my favorite security
researchers&ndash;I highly recommend his talks. This talk was funny and informative.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Rogers">How to Hack a Tesla Model S - Marc Rogers and Kevin
Mahaffey</a>. Tesla did an amazing job of securing their
vehicle&ndash;especially considering how connected it is.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#AmmonRa">How to hack your way out of home detention -
AmmonRa</a>. Neat idea. Fake the messages from your
ankle bracelet while you cloak your existing one with a Faraday cage. You could get someone else in trouble by making
them appear outside their confinement zone too.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#L%C3%B8ge">Tell me who you are and I will tell you your lock pattern - Marte
Løge</a>. Turns out, people are predictable. And lock codes
maybe aren&rsquo;t all that secure.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Rock">I Will Kill You - Chris Rock</a>. <em>My favorite talk at
DEFCON 23.</em> Our birth and death record-keeping needs some modernization.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Sandvik">When IoT attacks: hacking a Linux-powered rifle - Runa A. Sandvik &amp; Michael
Auger</a>. Sad to see an Austin-based company taken
down, but come on&ndash;an internet-enabled rifle? you knew this was coming.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#McGrew">I Hunt Penetration Testers: More Weaknesses in Tools and Procedures - Wesley
McGrew</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Shoshitaishvili">Angry Hacking - the next generation of binary analysis - Yan Shoshitaishvili &amp; Fish
Wang</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Miller">Remote exploitation of an unaltered passenger vehicle - Charlie Miller and Chris
Valasek</a>. Dr. Miller and Chris Valasek are always
entertaining. Their presentation style is unlike any others&ndash;they either rehearse a ton or they have great chemistry and
complementary personalities. This continued their work hacking Jeeps. At the time of the talk, their exploits had been
fixed so all is well&hellip; for now.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Ryan">Hacking Electric Skateboards: Vehicle Research For Mortals - Mike Ryan &amp; Richo
Healey</a>. The timing on this was awesome! This came right
after the &ldquo;hack a Jeep&rdquo; talk and the humility of the presenters (&ldquo;vehicle research for mortals&rdquo;) was great. Basically,
if you build an internet- or bluetooth-enabled device, you will get hacked.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Kaminsky">I  want these * bugs off my * Internet - Dan
Kaminsky</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Talabis">The Bieber Project: Ad Tech 101, Fake Fans and Adventures in Buying Internet Traffic - Mark Ryan
Talabis</a>. Online ads baffle me. I think it is really
hard to connect ads to revenue, with an underlying belief that ads are not a wise use of capital. The presenter showed a
Chinese ad fraud system called jingling that spawns a ton of threads and programmatically clicks links; while running
jingling you accumulate tokens that you spend to get others to click on your links. Some people claim to make an extra
$50/day (or far more) just by participating. Brilliant!</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Sunday</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Domas">REpsych: Psychological Warfare in Reverse Engineering - Chris
Domas</a>. I missed the first half, but what I gathered is
that Chris Domas was able to figure out how to create binaries that form images when viewed in a disassembler like IDA.
He showed a silly malware that dynamically found images on your computer and made binaries that match the images&ndash;he
joked that he would stop probing any malware that could present his portrait.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Wardle2">Stick That In Your (root)Pipe &amp; Smoke It - Patrick
Wardle</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Coskun">Why nation-state malwares target Telco Networks: Dissecting technical capabilities of Regin and its counterparts - Omer
Coskun</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Lawshae">Let&rsquo;s Talk About SOAP, Baby. Let&rsquo;s Talk About UPNP - Ricky &ldquo;HeadlessZeke&rdquo;
Lawshae</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read March 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-march-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-march-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple long books this month.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015DPXKI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015DPXKI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Anathem by Neal
Stephenson</a>.
Hmm. I love Neal Stephenson&ndash;Diamond Age is one of my favorite books
ever&ndash;but this book didn&rsquo;t do it for me. I didn&rsquo;t get it. It was
intelligent and well researched&ndash;it just wasn&rsquo;t for me.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">The Well of Ascension by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
Book Two of the Mistborn trilogy. It started slowly, but ended well. Let
me expand on that a bit: the first book&ndash;to me&ndash;was about a rebellion in
a novel low-magic world. The second book has to pick up the pieces of
that rebellion, so it&rsquo;s more about government and interpersonal
conflicts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//sxsw-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//sxsw-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed myself a lot at SXSW 2015. I made it to a lot of sessions that were interesting and thought-provoking.</p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li>Welcome to SXSW Interactive by Hugh Forest</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997613">The Climate Crisis: Challenge and Opportunity by Al Gore</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996684">How to Rock SXSW in 4 Hours by Tim Ferriss</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42182">Fear, Shame, Empathy, &amp; More Ways to Change Behavior by Dan Pink</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40327">Building Gender-Balanced Startups (Panel) by Sarah Buhr, Julie Ann Horvath, Stewart Alsop, Vanessa Camones</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39145">OAuth2: The Swiss-Army Framework by Brent Shaffer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP41723">Patagonia: Why Business Is Good for the Planet by Rose Marcario</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42485">UFC: Women Breaking Ground Inside the Octagon (Panel) by Dana White, Ronda Rousey, Jessica Eye</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996358">Princess Reema&rsquo;s Mission to Empower Saudi Women by Princess Reema</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43837">What it Really Takes to Win in Business by Jack Welch and Gary Vaynerchuk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP37185">Beyond Privacy: Surveillance&rsquo;s Threat To Liberty by Schneier and Wizner</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Sunday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39695">Transgender in Tech: Past, Present, Future (Panel) by Allyson Dylan Robinson, Brielle Harrison, Kortney Ziegler, and Meghan Stabler</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43232">Be Epic: The Art of Bold Decision Making by Phil Libin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996157">AI, Immortality and the Future of Selves by Martine Rothblatt</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36963">Data (in)Security: MIT Scientists Tackle Privacy (Panel) by Danny Weitzner, Ronald Rivest, Sam Madden</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43378">How to Fix American Politics by David Burstein</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Monday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43236">The Frontiers of Computational Thinking by Stephen Wolfram</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43059">Everything Eric Ries Has Learned Since 2011 by Eric Ries</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996700">Fixing Transportation with Humanity and Technology by Logan Green</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996698">Lessons from BuzzFeed by Jonah Peretti</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996699">Bitcoin: What It Needs to Succeed (Panel) by the Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tuesday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40699">Accelerators by the Numbers: 2014 Rankings by Susan Cohen and Yael Hochberg</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996685">Better and Faster: Predict Opportunity &amp; Win in 2015 by Jeremy Grutsche</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997484">Holacracy: A Radical New Approach to Management by Brian Robertson</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996703">Moonshots and Reality by Astro Teller</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36218">How to Rob a Bank: Vulnerabilities of New Money by Josh Alexander, Bo Hartman, Bob Blakely</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read February 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-february-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-february-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One really long book dominated my reading this this month&ndash;I only
finished two books, but they were both very good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009JNXC36/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009JNXC36&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre
Dumas</a>.
This book is a classic for a reason. I prefer modern books, but I
decided to give Count of Monte Cristo a try, and I&rsquo;m glad I did.
The story was really good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DYXC3W8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DYXC3W8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Warbound by Larry
Correia</a>.
I&rsquo;m really enjoying Larry Correia. He has the adventure fantasy story down. His
novels are fun and well-paced with memorable characters, and they feel
like the right amount of story per book. Warbound
concludes the Grimnoir Chronicles, providing a fitting finish.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read January 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-january-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-january-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">Mistborn by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
A solid fantasty novel with an interesting magic system. In Mistborn, a
select few people are gifted with the ability to burn a metal internally
granting them abilities like improved strength or improved hearing. The
elevated ability lasts as long as the metal remains with the metal
burning in proportion to the power you demand of it. An even smaller
group can burn all metals. I liked it a lot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/art-of-conflict-management-achieving-solutions-for-life-work-and-beyond.html">The Art of Conflict Management by Michael
Dues</a>.
I now think that conflict management is the most important skill a
person can have. I wish this stuff was taught in school! It was very
helpful for me to learn the basics, which provided me with a framework
for understanding conflict (&ldquo;discomforting differences&rdquo;).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AFPVOTG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AFPVOTG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=JWTMJY6TXCVPZDCO">Finding Your Element by Sir Ken
Robinson</a>. Ken Robinson had a great
tech talk, so I thought I&rsquo;d like the book. It was good, but not really
what I need. I&rsquo;d recommend the book to young people who are floundering as they embark on
adulthood or middle-aged people struggling to understand where they fit
into the scheme of things.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C438CW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004C438CW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=7XHAOVDX33VKT7OV">No More Mr. Nice Guy by Robert
Glover</a>. I don&rsquo;t know how to feel about this book. I think it has a lot of really good information for nice guys who are unfulfilled; however, it raises some questions regarding masculinity and being kind but firm. Some of the positive points: men should spend time with other men, people should stand up for themselves and they should get what they want, and couples should evenly divide work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read in 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s a recap of the books I read in 2015. They&rsquo;re roughly categorized as fiction followed by non-fiction.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">Mistborn by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">The Well of Ascension by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Hero of Ages by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Mitosis by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Way of Kings by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Words of Radiance by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Off-Wizard-Magic-2-0-Book-ebook/dp/B00EF8Z32I/?tag=theven01-20">Off to Be the Wizard by Scott Meyer</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Spell-High-Water-Magic-Book-ebook/dp/B00HVF7OJM/?tag=theven01-20">Spell or High Water by Scott Meyer</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Unwelcome-Quest-Magic-2-0-Book-ebook/dp/B00MRADM1K/?tag=theven01-20">An Unwelcome Quest by Scott Meyer</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Assassin&rsquo;s Apprentice by Robin Hobb</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Blade Itself by Joe Abercrombie</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Hexed by Kevin Hearne</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Under Heaven by Guy Gavriel Kay</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">14 by Peter Clines</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Hunters Unlucky by Abigail Hilton</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/11-22-63-Stephen-King-ebook/dp/B005K0HDGE/?tag=theven01-20">11-22-63 by Stephen King</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009JNXC36/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009JNXC36&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre
Dumas</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Chimes by Charles Dickens</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Snow Queen by Hans Christian Andersen</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DYXC3W8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DYXC3W8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Warbound by Larry
Correia</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015DPXKI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015DPXKI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Anathem by Neal
Stephenson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Things to shout out loud at parties. by Markus Almond</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Jesus&#8217; Son by Denis Johnson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Elantris by Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>

<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/art-of-conflict-management-achieving-solutions-for-life-work-and-beyond.html">The Art of Conflict Management by Michael
Dues</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AFPVOTG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AFPVOTG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=JWTMJY6TXCVPZDCO">Finding Your Element by Sir Ken
Robinson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C438CW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004C438CW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=7XHAOVDX33VKT7OV">No More Mr. Nice Guy by Robert
Glover</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/How-Fail-Almost-Everything-Still-ebook/dp/B00COOFBA4/?tag=theven01-20">How to Fail At Almost Everything and Still Win Big by Scott Adams</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Great-Ways-Manage-Double-Productivity/dp/B0017182XI/?tag=theven01-20">21 Great Ways to Manage Your Time and Double Your Productivity by Brian Tracy</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Choose-Yourself-James-Altucher-ebook/dp/B00CO8D3G4/?tag=theven01-20">Choose Yourself by James Altucher</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Choose Yourself Guide to Wealth by James Altucher</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practicing-Power-Now-Eckhart-Tolle-ebook/dp/B002361MNS/?tag=theven01-20">Practicing the Power of Now by Eckhart Tolle</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Obstacle-Way-Timeless-Turning-Triumph-ebook/dp/B00G3L1B8K/?tag=theven01-20">The Obstacle is the Way by Ryan Holiday</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Will-Teach-You-Be-Rich-ebook/dp/B004WL4BW6/?tag=theven01-20">I Will Teach You to Be Rich by Ramit Sethi</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/100-Startup-Reinvent-Living-Create/dp/0307951529/?tag=theven01-20">The $100 Startup by Chris Guillebeau</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Trust-Me-Lying-Confessions-Manipulator-ebook/dp/B0074VTHH0/?tag=theven01-20">Trust Me, I&rsquo;m Lying by Ryan Holiday</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Becoming a Technical Leader by Gerald Weinberg</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Phoenix Project by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, and George Spafford</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Radical Acceptance by Tara Brach</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Charisma Myth by Olivia Fox Cabane</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">So You&rsquo;ve Been Publicly Shamed by Jon Ronson</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Contagious by Jonah Berger</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Waking Up by Sam Harris</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">Growth Hacker Marketing by Ryan Holiday</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Art of Asking by Amanda Palmer</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">The Willpower Instinct by Kelly McGonigal</a>.</p>

<p><a href="">From Transgender to Transhuman by Martine Goldblatt</a>.</p>

<h3>To blog or to Goodreads</h3>

<p>I haven&rsquo;t decided how I prefer to track what I&rsquo;ve read. You can see <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/48474315-seth?shelf=read">my attempt at using Goodreads here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read December 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-december-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-december-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a busy month for reading. Lots of good stuff!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00ARSJNW6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00ARSJNW6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KQP7U6OB4WMDL2XX">Dracula Chronicles: Son of the Dragon by Victor
Foia</a>. An interesting retelling of the life of Dracula. This book, the first of three, tracks Dracula in his teenage years as he makes his first kill. The book was really good, but I was looking for more fantasy.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00APA1NK6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00APA1NK6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=WMOFDYAVZR4UFKHT">Spellbound by Larry
Correia</a>. Correia has the fantasy adventure
story down. Very entertaining. I look forward to finishing the series
(Grimnoir Chronicles) soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CD360ZQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00CD360ZQ&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KKUCVAWJ3O2JOMPV">Alas, Babylon by Pat
Frank</a>. A slice of life in the alternate reality
where the cold war ended with nuclear war. I could see this
book as the precursor to The Road by McCarthy. I liked it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D4CBA50/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00D4CBA50&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KN3MMS2ERWTKFAU7">At the Mountains of Madness by H.P.
Lovecraft</a>. Beware the elder
things buried in Antarctica.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00COOFBA4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00COOFBA4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=U74HXIB7CQ3OEZNU">How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big by Scott
Adams</a>. Scott Adams is the creator of the workplace comic, <a href="http://www.dilbert.com/">Dilbert</a>. In this book Adams lays out his lessons on life. Some of the high points: eat well, exercise, get into a routine, optimize your personal energy, learn as many different skills as you can (because success is likely to come from some combination of your skills), and passion is just a fancy way for successful people to say they got lucky. I really liked the book; I thought it was funny and informative, and I loved the humility with which the story was told. Where many books and life stories rewrite history and show how one success begot another, Adams instead talks about how his failures lead to success. The anecdotes were modest and on-point, which I found refreshing and brave.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009U9S6FI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009U9S6FI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3S6RUEUONCG3UEAU">Man&rsquo;s Search for Meaning by Viktor
Frankl</a>. A Jewish psychiatrist&rsquo;s
Holocaust story helps explain his world view and motivate his
psychotherapy approach,
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy">Logotherapy</a>. I appreciated
that the book was honest without dwelling too much on the atrocities:
rather than recounting every terrible thing that happened, Frankl picks
a few key events that provide a broad understanding. Remarkably, Frankl
does something constructive with his grief. In the book he mentions that
Logotherapy might ask a patient why that patient does not commit
suicide because the answer reveals your meaning, which you can then work
with to heal. One of the most disturbing parts of the book for me was
Frankl&rsquo;s account of returning home to a nation that ignored the
concentration camps or downplayed their significance; he writes that for
many survivors life after the camp was harder than life in the camp.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009AYWPCI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009AYWPCI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=XSJDV3OEBODUC5IH">Futures and Frosting by Tara
Sivec</a>. Futures and Frosting tells the
story of how a single-mother is reunited with the father of her child;
after a lot of confusion, the couple gets married and has another kid,
then lives happily ever after. Without the humor, it would read like
an angsty young adult love story.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596518382/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596518382&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=HYDQVVVHWRDD54ZB">Apprenticeship Patterns by Dave Hoover and Ade
Oshineye</a>.
This was probably the most accessible technical book I&rsquo;ve read. The
application of pattern language to a career is really clever and worked
well. As with software patterns, it&rsquo;s nice to see the path.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read November 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-november-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-november-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591845327/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1591845327&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=CRLWDIV34KA7TYF3">Leaders Eat Last by Simon
Sinek</a>. I loved this book because it
resonated with my hopes for the future of business. Sinek also brought
in some of my favorite psychological ideas in a way that I found
inspiring&ndash;I&rsquo;ve read a lot of the same research and come across the same
ideas, but I had not synthesized the data into a coherent worldview.
I&rsquo;d boil it down to the following: short-term profit maximization is
proving unsustainable even harmful for society; instead, you should treat
employees as people to enjoy sustained growth.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FC10MU/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000FC10MU&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=GQKSUWEFX3EOXXTL">American Gods by Neil
Gaiman</a>. Based on numerous positive reviews I
was really excited to read this book; unfortunately, I didn&rsquo;t care much
for it. In the preface Gaiman says that the book is long and meandering,
and he hit the nail on the head. I thought the main plot was pretty
interesting, but the tangents did not add anything for me. At times it
felt like I was reading a book for English class because I just didn&rsquo;t
understand the message.</p>

<p><a href="ttp://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00FCQQCX6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00FCQQCX6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=ZEIIG5IJ2ZYDFWFL">The Emperor&rsquo;s Blades by Brian
Stavely</a>. I liked the book, but I&rsquo;m not
sure I&rsquo;m ready for another series just yet.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Poor-Economics-rethinking-poverty-ways-ebook/dp/B007CI81IQ/ref=sr_1_1?tag=theven01-20">Poor Economics by Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo</a>. An accessible summary
of research about poor people worldwide. I loved the realistic approach
to helping people. Some of my favorite tidbits were that people donated
significantly more money when the message focused on a single,
identifiable person and that when given money, poor people tend to buy
more interesting food rather than more of the same (in the studies
people still ate around 1200 calories but they would incorporated more
meat and indulgences like tea rather than eating another 500 calories of
rice).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/language-a-to-z.html">Language A to Z by John
McWhorter</a>. Great course by the Great
Courses.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/customs-of-the-world-using-cultural-intelligence-to-adapt-wherever-you-are.html">Customs of the World by David
Livermore</a>. Good course by the Great
Courses.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read October 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-october-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-october-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000OI0G1Q/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000OI0G1Q&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=GO6FQAOF57SDDYD4">The Road by Cormac
McCarthy</a>. A short but powerful book&ndash;I see why it was made into a movie. Turns out the apocalypse is no fun.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005IHWBSY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B005IHWBSY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=27ID6XF3TZLBRUHR">God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater by Kurt
Vonnegut</a>. I&rsquo;m ashamed to admit that this is my first Vonnegut book. I&rsquo;ve broken the seal, and I enjoyed it. The book has a socialist bent, so I&rsquo;d love to hear what a strong capitalist thought of this book.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006LSZECO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B006LSZECO&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=CTUBO5ECTNQJQN3S">Gone Girl by Gillian
Flynn</a>. I finished this before seeing the movie. My overall reaction is, &ldquo;wow.&rdquo; I didn&rsquo;t like it, then liked it, then loved it, then didn&rsquo;t like it. It was original and well written, for what that&rsquo;s worth.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0787960756/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0787960756&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Five Dysfunctions of a Team by Patrick
Lencioni</a>.
I&rsquo;ve now read a few Lencioni books, and I really enjoy them. I find his novel
approach to business lessons is very accessible. This book says you need
to first establish trust so that people will speak freely. Without
trust, people cannot engage in productive arguments, so people do not
buy in&ndash;they just quit arguing. Once you have trust, an open exchange of
ideas, and commitment to a shared vision, you can start holding people
accountable. Finally, you can focus on results. The five dysfunctions
are presented as a pyramid, which highlights the need to achieve the
previous level before moving up&ndash;I thought that was kind of like
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow's_hierarchy_of_needs">Maslow&rsquo;s Hierarchy of
Needs</a> applied
to business.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
