<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-16T09:52:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why don't we improve air travel?]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/why-dont-we-improve-air-travel/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/why-dont-we-improve-air-travel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Everyday, millions of people fly. I&rsquo;d guess most everyone hates the process. As with most things in life, happy people make everything better (they&rsquo;re more productive, etc)&ndash;and it&rsquo;s contagious!</p>

<p>Terminals</p>

<ul>
<li>Better seating</li>
<li>More A/C outlets</li>
<li>Free wifi</li>
<li>Smoking rooms</li>
</ul>


<p>Flights</p>

<ul>
<li>Allow people to use electronic devices the whole time</li>
<li>Turn on the entertainment system and A/C before passengers board and leave them on until people are off the plane</li>
<li>USB charging stations on each seat</li>
<li>Assigned overhead bins</li>
<li>Some sane amount of free alcohol (maybe 1 drink per 4 hours)</li>
<li>A light snack (research points to about 300 calories per 3 hours)</li>
<li>Treat people like adults!</li>
</ul>


<p>There are some other ideas in <a title="Salon" href="http://www.salon.com/technology/ask_the_pilot/2010/09/15/airplane_seating/index.html" target="_blank">this article on Salon</a>.</p>

<p>Beyond these, improved communication and more travel options would be fantastic. What would you like to see?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The World Cup shows the ubiquity of English]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/the-world-cup-shows-the-ubiquity-of-english/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/the-world-cup-shows-the-ubiquity-of-english</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been enjoying the World Cup for the past three weeks&ndash;while still getting all of my work done, of course. One thing that has been really neat is seeing the diverse cultures communicating. I imagine the players and referees could play without words (we&rsquo;ll let them keep whistles and hand-signs), but very frequently players verbally plead for calls and the ref explicitly announces situations to players. The on-field interactions seem to be in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/English_language">English</a>.</p>

<p>When Paraguay, coached by an Argentinian, <a href="http://www.fifa.com/worldcup/matches/round=249718/match=300061506/index.html">played</a> Spain, coached by a Spaniard, they were officiated by a Guatemalan, Costa Rican, Honduran, and Mexican; I&rsquo;d guess everyone spoke Spanish. But the situation gets more complicated if we look at when Paraguay (native Spanish speakers) <a href="http://www.fifa.com/worldcup/matches/round=249717/match=300061497/index.html">played</a> Japan (native Japanese speakers) with refs from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Belgium">Belgium</a> (official languages are Dutch, French, and German). My lip-reading skills are admittedly amateur, but I perceived English. This has been the case throughout the tournament. Now, I&rsquo;m glad that I focused on furthering my English skills instead of futilely learning a foreign language because everyone speaks English. The World Cup taught me so :-)</p>

<p>So, when and how are players from all of the world learning English well enough to communicate with other similarly diverse English-speakers? When did this start? Because <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diego_Maradona">Maradona</a>, an old school footballer, interviews in Spanish using a translator.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Country's "real" name]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/countrys-real-name/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/countrys-real-name</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been wondering why we do not call a country by the name that the country calls itself? For example, <a title="wikipedia japan" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Japan" target="_blank">Japan</a> would be &ldquo;<span lang="ja" xml:lang="ja">??</span> Nihon or Nippon<sup><a title="Help:Japanese" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Help:Japanese"><span class="t nihongo icon" style="padding: 0pt 0.1em; color: #0000ee; font-family: sans-serif; font-style: normal; font-variant: normal; font-weight: bold; font-size: 80%; line-height: normal; font-size-adjust: none; font-stretch: normal; text-decoration: none;"></span></a></sup>&rdquo;;<a title="google maps of Spain" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=spain+map&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;oe=utf-8" target="_blank"> Spain</a> would be &ldquo;España&rdquo;; and <a title="CIA world factbook" href="https://www.cia.gov/library/publications/the-world-factbook/geos/gm.html" target="_blank">Germany </a>would be &ldquo;Deutschland&rdquo;.</p>

<p>I think using the country&rsquo;s internal name would engender a sense of community and increase cultural understanding. It could also help people to learn a new language because we would be exposed to more sounds than we are now.</p>

<p>The only problem I see is in countries with multiple languages (think India), there may be a number of internal names. However, if people would take the time to learn the name of your country, you may be more motivated to come up with an official name.</p>

<p>Good idea? Bad idea? Am I missing something?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
