<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rant | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/blog/categories/rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-22T14:10:39-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pleasing customers (DO IT)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/pleasing-customers-do-it/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/pleasing-customers-do-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if it&rsquo;s the economy or just bad luck, but my customer service experiences recently have been awful. Earlier this month <a title="Seth Holloway Dot Com" href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/?p=345" target="_blank">I was battling with World of Warcraft customer service</a> after a time zone mismatch ruined my fun. After several phone calls and over ten emails, the situation has been resolved&mdash;not fixed, resolved. They compensated me nicely, but ultimately they could not right the wrong. Overall, I am satisfied and will continue doing business with them. Unfortunately, it took far too long for me to be satisfied.</p>

<p>Now, a much more serious matter has come to light: Thailand, our a long-awaited December vacation destination, <a title="Google News" href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5gXtkIJGFlHXR5qT3LIG2olEVZyFQD94MV9780" target="_blank">has experienced a wave of protests that shut down international airports</a>. The non-violent protests forced Prime Minister Somchai Wongsawat out of power and led to huge headaches for foreigners in (or trying to get to) Thailand. The climate is not right for foreign travelers; <a title="JAL press release" href="http://www.ar.jal.com/cms/contents/en/special_news_107.html" target="_blank">Japan Airlines even stopped flights</a> and the US State Department <a title="official site" href="http://travel.state.gov/travel/cis_pa_tw/pa/pa_1998.html" target="_blank">recommended that Americans defer trips</a>.</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s the problem? Vayama (a company I won&rsquo;t even link because they have not earned it) will not refund our tickets despite the instability of the region and recent travel stoppages. They have done everything to frustrate me and waste my time without ever leaving me pleased. The first pass automated systems cannot answer my question, so I navigate confusing menus and deal with long waits before reaching a human. Finally, the human on the other end cannot help. A little good will goes a long way. Right now I do not plan to use Vayama again; the money they&rsquo;ve made off me now pales in comparison to the potential earnings if they had made a good impression.</p>

<p>Sadly, I&rsquo;ve encountered this workflow twice in a few weeks and it is all wrong. If you want to succeed in business, do the exact opposite of this. Customer service should have pleasing customers as a general goal. I understand this may cost more, but the funny thing about customers is that you want them and you won&rsquo;t get that when your representatives run all customers off.</p>

<p>Two of my favorite bloggers, <a title="Seth Godin" href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/" target="_blank">Seth Godin</a> and <a title="Joel On Software" href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/" target="_blank">Joel Spolsky</a>, have commented on the simple act of pleasing customers and the big impact it has. See <a title="Joel on Software: Excellent Customer Service" href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/customerservice.html" target="_blank">Joel&rsquo;s take on customer service</a> and <a title="Google search of Seth Godin's site" href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;domains=http%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F&amp;sitesearch=http%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F&amp;q=customer+service+site%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F&amp;btnG=Search&amp;sitesearch=http%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F" target="_blank">Seth&rsquo;s many posts</a>, especially <a title="Seth Godin Apologies Ranked" href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2007/02/apologies_ranke.html" target="_blank">apologies and what they mean</a> and the <a title="Seth Godin Creating a Clearance Culture" href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2008/11/creating-a-clea.html" target="_blank">clearance culture</a>.</p>

<p>My desperate plea to employers is really quite simple:</p>

<ul>
<li>Empower entry level customer service representatives to solve problems&mdash;they are the ones making an impression</li>
<li>Give customer service representatives  respect&mdash;they drive as many sales as the marketing department</li>
<li>Pay customer service representatives fairly&mdash;this may require hiring people of a worthy caliber</li>
<li>Offer customer service representatives a career path&mdash;again, you may have to be awake while hiring</li>
<li>Reduce the overhead in communications&mdash;reduce wait times, shorten telephone spiels, etc.</li>
<li>Go out of your way to thank and appreciate customers&mdash;your business does not exist without them!</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Frustration in submitting insurance claims]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/frustration-in-submitting-insurance-claims/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/frustration-in-submitting-insurance-claims</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently purchased contact lens from <a title="1800Contacts Web Site" href="http://www.1800contacts.com/" target="_blank">1800Contacts</a>. Now, I&rsquo;m trying to submit a claim to my vision insurance, <a title="Super Vision Homepage" href="http://www.superiorvision.com/" target="_blank">Superior Vision</a>. I am frustrated that the only claims options are fax or snail mail! I have no reason to believe that I will not receive my money, but I&rsquo;m frustrated at the lack of options at filing the claim.</p>

<p>Over the past several years I have been asked to fax a form. Everytime, I&rsquo;m left wondering who has a fax machine handy?</p>

<p>Furthermore, when will companies embrace the digital revolution? I&rsquo;ve scanned the receipt and my insurance card, but there&rsquo;s no email address that I can send it to. Using digital methods would save me, the consumer, and the company time and frustration.</p>

<p>Also, if fax machines are still being used widely, why is there not an open standard for email-to-fax machines?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Local news: show me the weather!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/local-news-show-me-the-weather/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/local-news-show-me-the-weather</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On my bike ride in ths morning I was thinking about weather <a title="Seth Holloway Aug 09, 2008 Post" href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/?p=102" target="_blank">again</a>. While getting ready this morning I had the TV on. I would do a task then check the TV&mdash;no weather&mdash;so I&rsquo;d do another task and check the TV&mdash;still no weather. All the while the news icon is taunting me in the bottom left corner of the screen. The simple graphic states the affiliate name and the temperature in a given area. Fox, NBC, CBS, ABC, and News 8 Austin were all roughtly the same icon. Why not put an umbrella sign if it is likely to rain?</p>

<p>Seriously. Augment the current graphic with an unobtrusive umbrella icon. Simple. Clean. Efficient. Helpful. Personally, I would still have the channel on for a few minutes each morning, so the channels do not need to worry about ratings. If anything, I&rsquo;d watch the channel more often because they would reliably give me the information I wanted. except I would leave the house more informed and happier. I can dream!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pirated material is worth what?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/pirated-material-is-worth-what/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/pirated-material-is-worth-what</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a title="Seth Holloway Dot Com" href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/?p=72" target="_blank">Yesterday</a> I pointed to a story where a woman paid $756 per song. However, that number is completely arbitrary and steadily decreasing. In a recent <a title="DVDs are worth $19 each" href="http://blog.wired.com/27bstroke6/2008/08/mpaa-waffling-o.html" target="_blank">prosecution of a man in New Orleans</a>, the MPAA claimed that pirated DVDs were worth $19 each. In another case, the RIAA said that pirated CDs are worth $13.74 a piece. If a CD has 20 songs, a single song definitely isn&rsquo;t worth $756. Every case states a different value for pirated material, but whenever it comes to scaring legislators (hardly the critical bunch), the rhetoric becomes clear: pirated material is costing America billions of dollars a year.</p>

<p>The RIAA and MPAA have successfully <a title="Colleges Help Us Catch Your Students Bill" href="http://edlabor.house.gov/bills/HEAReauthorizationText.pdf">created legislation</a> based on trumped-up numbers. There are so many factors beyond piracy that have led to decreased sales. First of all, consumers have no way to find new music and films. In the 1990s, MTV actually played music; now, the network only plays reality TV. A major avenue for finding music is all but closed. If less people are watching TV and movies, why would a bulk of your advertising be placed in those mediums? Instead, sites like Pandora, Muxtape, YouTube, etc that expose people to a multitude of music are being shut down or having content forced down with nasty DMCA takedown notices.</p>

<p>Add in the fact that kids are getting sued for trying out new music (downloads do not mean that a person does not own own the item nor do they imply that a person will not buy the good later) which inflames people. While I cannot speak for everyone, I have stopped buying CDs (I don&rsquo;t even download the music&mdash;I just don&rsquo;t listen to anything) after the zealous prosecution of consumers. No successful business model is based on suing your customers; it bites the litigious ones in the butt.</p>

<p>Beyond that, the music has become grossly commercial. At a time when people are rushing to be individuals, music and film have become completely homogenous. TV has become increasingly diverse; cable networks like USA are doing well with unique shows such as Burn Notice and Psych. However, ratings overall are down while total viewership has increased. People are embracing their niche and business should follow suit.</p>

<p>Lastly, the economy has been slowing for years. If people have less money, or feel less secure in their future, discretionary spending will decrease. That means music and movie sales will decrease. That&rsquo;s just life in a free market. Some businesses fail.</p>

<p>The American public is paying for the RIAA&rsquo;s and MPAA&rsquo;s inability to adapt to a changing market. Consumers have less money and fewer options to find new movies and music; we are being sued by content producers; and the product being offered is not to our liking. Fix these issues. Stop creating unnecessary laws and pursuing frivolous lawsuits.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Annoying commercials]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/annoying-commercials/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/annoying-commercials</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I won&rsquo;t validate the ads by pointing them out, but we can all think of a number of annoying commercials. I suppose the marketeers who generated these wretched pieces truly believe that &ldquo;no press is bad press.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t focus groups give feedback? I can&rsquo;t imagine anyone seeing such choice pieces of advertising and saying, &ldquo;YEAH! I want to buy X now!&rdquo;</p>

<p>More and more ads are moving online, but no one knows what works in online advertising. I block obnoxious ads online, but allow non-obtrusive, possibly even helpful, ads. Last night Mike and I discussed when we click on Google ads&mdash;and it&rsquo;s not when Google would like us to (i.e. all the time). I have to wonder if I&rsquo;m the standard user or a corner case. What brave new world awaits us with advertising?</p>

<p>By the way, I avoid most ads by using <a title="download firefox!" href="http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/" target="_blank">Firefox</a> with <a title="must have firefox add-on!" href="http://adblockplus.org" target="_blank">Adblock Plus</a>. If you&rsquo;re not already using these two, I&rsquo;d highly recommend it. (More to come later on this subject.) Opera 10 has built in ad-blocking although I don&rsquo;t find it works as well. To augment the service you can use Admuncher (I don&rsquo;t link because they charge a lot) or any other technique described on <a title="Ad filtering article on wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_filtering" target="_blank">wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
