<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rant | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-15T18:32:12-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pleasing customers (DO IT)]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/pleasing-customers-do-it/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/pleasing-customers-do-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if it&rsquo;s the economy or just bad luck, but my customer service experiences recently have been awful. Customer service should have pleasing customers as a general goal. I understand this may cost more, but the funny thing about customers is that you want them and you won&rsquo;t get that when your representatives run all customers off.</p>

<p>Two of my favorite bloggers, <a title="Seth Godin" href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/" target="_blank">Seth Godin</a> and <a title="Joel On Software" href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/" target="_blank">Joel Spolsky</a>, have commented on the simple act of pleasing customers and the big impact it has. See <a title="Joel on Software: Excellent Customer Service" href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/articles/customerservice.html" target="_blank">Joel&rsquo;s take on customer service</a> and <a title="Google search of Seth Godin's site" href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;domains=http%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F&amp;sitesearch=http%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F&amp;q=customer+service+site%3Ahttp%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F&amp;btnG=Search&amp;sitesearch=http%3A%2F%2Fsethgodin.typepad.com%2F" target="_blank">Seth&rsquo;s many posts</a>, especially <a title="Seth Godin Apologies Ranked" href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2007/02/apologies_ranke.html" target="_blank">apologies and what they mean</a> and the <a title="Seth Godin Creating a Clearance Culture" href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2008/11/creating-a-clea.html" target="_blank">clearance culture</a>.</p>

<p>My desperate plea to employers is really quite simple:</p>

<ul>
<li>Empower entry level customer service representatives to solve problems&ndash;they are the ones making an impression</li>
<li>Give customer service representatives  respect&ndash;they drive as many sales as the marketing department</li>
<li>Pay customer service representatives fairly&ndash;this may require hiring people of a worthy caliber</li>
<li>Offer customer service representatives a career path&ndash;again, you may have to be awake while hiring</li>
<li>Reduce the overhead in communications&ndash;reduce wait times, shorten telephone spiels, etc.</li>
<li>Go out of your way to thank and appreciate customers&ndash;your business does not exist without them!</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Annoying commercials]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/annoying-commercials/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/annoying-commercials</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I won&rsquo;t validate the ads by pointing them out, but we can all think of a number of annoying commercials. I suppose the marketeers who generated these wretched pieces truly believe that &ldquo;no press is bad press.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t focus groups give feedback? I can&rsquo;t imagine anyone seeing such choice pieces of advertising and saying, &ldquo;YEAH! I want to buy X now!&rdquo;</p>

<p>More and more ads are moving online, but no one knows what works in online advertising. I block obnoxious ads online, but allow non-obtrusive, possibly even helpful, ads. Last night Mike and I discussed when we click on Google ads&ndash;and it&rsquo;s not when Google would like us to (i.e. all the time). I have to wonder if I&rsquo;m the standard user or a corner case. What brave new world awaits us with advertising?</p>

<p>By the way, I avoid most ads by using <a title="download firefox!" href="http://www.mozilla.com/firefox/" target="_blank">Firefox</a> with <a title="must have firefox add-on!" href="http://adblockplus.org" target="_blank">Adblock Plus</a>. If you&rsquo;re not already using these two, I&rsquo;d highly recommend it. (More to come later on this subject.) Opera 10 has built in ad-blocking although I don&rsquo;t find it works as well. To augment the service you can use Admuncher (I don&rsquo;t link because they charge a lot) or any other technique described on <a title="Ad filtering article on wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_filtering" target="_blank">wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Driving laws]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/driving-laws/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/driving-laws</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The joke goes that 98% of people consider themselves good drivers. Driving is such a tangible effort: everyone over the age of 16 can drive. Because that captures such a large percentage of the population, there are a number of ideas about how to drive. As I see it, traffic laws should be obeyed in spirit rather than completely literally.</p>

<p>Basic driving rules:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Keep right!</strong> If someone is going slower than you would like to go, pass them on the left and return to the right</li>
<li><strong>Do not drive on the heel of another car!</strong> This goes with number 1 but represents a separate idea to which attention should be paid. do not hover behind a nearby vehicle: it is obnoxious to anyone trying to pass and it is dangerous because you may be in someone&rsquo;s blind spot.</li>
<li><strong>Know the speed limit at all times!</strong> Going under the speed limit hurts both you and others on the road. the government chooses a speed limit based on safety concerns and the average speed observed in an area. do not try to circumvent the law and drive at a lower speed&ndash;they&rsquo;ve already set the lower limit for you. Going less than speed limit increases your commute time and likely increases the amount of gasoline wasted on idling. By driving slowly you are also slowing the general flow of traffic so your decision triggers a loss of time for everyone around you.</li>
<li><strong>Travel at the speed limit to 7mph over speed limit at all times!</strong> In addition to knowing the speed limit, driving at 0-7 mph over the speed limit insulates you from 95% of speeding tickets and gets you places faster. Some basic calculations. One ticket a year costs an average of $100 ($50 administrative + $50 for defensive driving). If you are paid $20 an hour, the ticket is worthwhile if you can save 5 hours of time a year from driving. If you drive an average of 20 miles a day, 300 days a year, then you drive 6000 miles a year. with an average posted speed limit of 45mph, driving an average of 47mph will save 5.67 hours over the course of a year without appreciably increasing your chances to get a ticket. Driving the extra 2mph is clearly worth your effort.</li>
<li><strong>Get happy!</strong> Leave the road rage at home. If you accomplish this, please tell me how!</li>
</ul>


<p>The other day <a title="Andrea Mire Holloway home" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andreamholloway">Andrea</a> pointed out a disturbing trend: people driving with earphones in (<em>cough iPod cough</em>). Initially, I agreed without much thought; however, she went on to say that the disturbing part is that even people with nice cars are doing it. After she pointed it out, I&rsquo;ve seen people in all kinds of cars from Fords to Mercedez throwing caution to the wind and driving with deafening music pumping directly into their eardrums. As a corollary, not a full rule, listen to music through your cars radio!</p>

<p>I imagine I&rsquo;m missing some other rules, but I think this is a good start.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cell phones in public]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/cell-phones-in-public/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/cell-phones-in-public</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some people assert that cell phones are the rudest device ever unleashed on the world. While this may true, we cannot forget that all the people talking on cell phones are being more social while simultaneously being less social. Every sorority girl flapping her gums when she should have both hands on the wheel is communicating with another person. Every communication brings us closer to one another and closer to ourselves. In that regard, all these rude phone conversations that keep a person from interacting with the outside world are bringing the conversants closer to a select few. All in all I have felt the cold shoulder hefted upon me when someone chooses to speak on their cell phone instead of to me, but I have to think positively and credit them for interacting at all&ndash;unlike those iPod listeners&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
