<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: review | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//"/>
  <updated>2016-06-30T19:53:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Midori sushi is great!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//midori-sushi-is-great/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//midori-sushi-is-great</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night we went to <a title="Homepage currently down :-\" href="http://www.midorisushiaustin.com/" target="_blank">Midori</a>, a sushi/Asian food restaurant in NW Austin. <a title="Only website you need...EVAR" href="http://www.laneholloway.com" target="_blank">Lane</a> went here for his birthday meal and liked it. I was really excited after I read the <a title="Yelp: Midori" href="http://www.yelp.com/biz/midori-sushi-austin" target="_blank">overwhelmingly positive reviews</a>. Even the local Fox affiliates foodie, <a title="Rob Balon on Midori" href="http://www.diningoutwithrobbalon.com/review/midori/" target="_blank">Rob Balon, loved it</a>!</p>

<p>After eating there I must say that I was impressed. Everything was absolutely delicious! The miso was a treat; the house salad was fresh and satisfying; the teriyaki was superb; and the sushi was fantastic. I recommend the Boca Raton roll which is similar to Maru&rsquo;s J-Bomb, but way less spicy.</p>

<p>Beyond great food the place has ambience. The interior is very clean; the restaurant is decorated with Japanese-looking pieces. Waitresses wear traditional Japanese garb and the sushi chefs welcome you with a Japanese &ldquo;hello&rdquo;&mdash;I&rsquo;ve been watching anime long enough to know some Japanese! Fun.</p>

<p>I will be returning to Midori!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weekend o' movies]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//weekend-o-movies/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//weekend-o-movies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend we saw <a title="Tropic Thunder IMDB" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0942385/" target="_blank">Tropic Thunder</a>, <a title="Forgetting Sarah Marshall IMDB" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0800039/" target="_blank">Forgetting Sarah Marshall</a>, and <a title="Talladega Nights on IMDB" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0415306/" target="_blank">Talladega Nights: The Ballad of Ricky Bobby</a>. All three were worth watching and hilarious! Incidentally, I ranked them in order of descending hilarity above. And I&rsquo;m justified because the <a title="Internet Movie Database" href="http://www.imdb.com" target="_blank">IMDB</a> voters seem to agree!</p>

<p>Recently I had been thinking that we did not have enough comedies. It turns out I just hadn&rsquo;t seen them! These movies represent a general cross section of the comic superstars of the past 10 years. We&rsquo;re missing a few big names like Adam Sandler, Vince Vaughn, Steve Carell, and the South Park guys; however, we get Ben Stiller, Will Ferrell, Jack Black, the Judd Apatow crew (Paul Rudd, Jason Segel, Bill Hader, Jonah Hill, etc) and a few newcomers. This year&rsquo;s MTV Movie Awards host, Russell Brand, was funny (not laugh out loud, but pleasant smile) in Forgetting Sarah Marshall. Also, after Pineapple Express (which was also hilarious, although a little long) I&rsquo;m a big fan of Danny McBride&mdash;&ldquo;thug life!&rdquo; Danny was funny in Tropic Thunder. Although I don&rsquo;t think of him as a comediam per se, Robert Downey Jr. was a riot.</p>

<p>And now the baby Jesus and I are off to drink some Booty Sweat energy drink while watching the musical Dracula. (That&rsquo;s right, all three movies alluded to in one genius sequence of words).</p>

<p>Happy Labor Day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Listen to Mike Doughty]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//listen-to-mike-doughty/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//listen-to-mike-doughty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If I were asked for just one music recommendation, my choice would be <a title="official site" href="http://www.mikedoughty.com/" target="_blank">Mike Doughty</a>. Mike is the enigmatic &ldquo;Doughty&rdquo;, the lead singer of now defunct acid-jazz/rock/folk/hip-hop band <a title="soul coughing on wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soul_Coughing" target="_blank">Soul Coughing</a>. If you&rsquo;re looking for music done right, check Mike out!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 2008 Presidential Election]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//the-2008-presidential-election/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//the-2008-presidential-election</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, the campaign trail is heating up (meaning talk of the Olympics and Russia&rsquo;s invasion of Georgia have taken a back burner) as Obama and McCain announce their running mates. I&rsquo;ll preface my comments by saying that I am fiscally conservative and socially liberal&mdash;in other words, libertarian. (I believe that everyone follows that same ideology (whether they realize it or not), but that&rsquo;s beside the point.) I believe in a multi-party system where with candidates who have solid opinions and personal integrity. As such, I will not vote for either of the two major contenders, but I still have a few comments about each.</p>

<p><a title="Trust in Wikipedia!" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_McCain" target="_blank">McCain</a></p>

<p>When is the last time he even <a title="McCain has an awful lot of NV (no vote cast)" href="http://www.votesmart.org/voting_category.php?can_id=53270" target="_blank">did his job as a senator</a>? Can we really trust him to do his job as president, or will he <a title="Bush set a record for most vacation" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2005/08/02/AR2005080201703_pf.html" target="_blank">spend months on his ranch</a>? Beyond his less than stellar track record, he&rsquo;s using some old-school negative advertisements. Finally, the guy is old. Considering him as an average white male who is almost 72, <a title="US Gov Data on Life Expectancy" href="http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/data/hus/hus07.pdf#027" target="_blank">he has about 10 years left</a>. Personally, I want someone with a little more vigor.</p>

<p><a title="Trust in Wikipedia!" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Obama" target="_blank">Obama</a></p>

<p>He&rsquo;s young and naive. I&rsquo;m worried that the candidate campaigning for change is moving more and more to the center&mdash;where politics have been for years. An entire generation behind this charismatic rock-star politician. Imagine their dismay when the candidate for change turns out to be the same-old hack. He already <a title="you know the story" href="http://abcnews.go.com/Blotter/Story?id=4443788" target="_blank">abandoned his pastor of 20 years</a>, what&rsquo;s to say he won&rsquo;t continue to slough off the very things we believed in him for? Someone should make Obama <a title="Kerry Flip Flops" href="http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?file=/c/a/2004/09/23/MNGQK8TI8O1.DTL" target="_blank">flip-flops.</a></p>

<p>Second, as an American who has traveled abroad in the past eight years, I know how much the rest of the world dislikes us. We have to repair our tarnished image. The Clinton war machine would have been a better choice on this front.</p>

<p>In the end, it&rsquo;s not up to me; it is up to everyone. May the best person win.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For The Bible Tells Me So]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//for-tthe-bible-tells-me-so/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//for-tthe-bible-tells-me-so</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week Andrea and I watched an <a title="8/10 on IMDB" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0912583/" target="_blank">excellent</a> documentary on homophobia titled &ldquo;<a title="official website" href="http://www.forthebibletellsmeso.org/index2.htm" target="_blank">For the Bible Tells Me So</a>&rdquo;. The film shows how little people know about the Bible verses that they use to justify hatred. You hear the tale of many different people and wraps things nicely in the end. While the story centers around homosexuality, the overriding themes can be applied to any bigoted subject. It is very politically correct and liberal, but I was moved.</p>

<p>A number of recent documentaries are made more watchable by tying the vignettes together to tell a story. Combine our love of reality TV with our desire for a plotline, and viola! instant classic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
