<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-25T09:15:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DEFCON 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/defcon-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/defcon-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DEFCON 23 was my favorite DEFCON experience so far. There were a lot of great talks and fun after-hours events. Below is
a list of talks that I attended, for posterity&rsquo;s sake.</p>

<h2>Thursday</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Reed">Hardware and Trust Security: Explain it like I’m 5 &ndash; Teddy Reed and Nick
Anderson</a></p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Szakaly">Shall We Play a Game? &ndash; Tamas Szakaly</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Drake">Stagefright: Scary Code in the Heart of Android &ndash; Joshua J.
Drake</a>. This talk explained the Android exploits that
arise because Android pre-processes incoming messages. For example, texting a malicious image leads Android to retrieve
and load the payload before the user even sees a notification. This should make the user interface feel faster, but it
comes at a price.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Schneier">Bruce Schneier Q&amp;A &ndash; Bruce Schneier</a>. I &lt;3 Bruce.
He&rsquo;s just so clear and intelligent. I hope we make him head of cyber security for the U.S.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Kamkar">Drive It Like You Hacked It: New Attacks and Tools to Wirelessly Steal Cars &ndash; Samy
Kamkar</a>. Samy is one of my favorite security
researchers&mdash;I highly recommend his talks. This talk was funny and informative.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Rogers">How to Hack a Tesla Model S &ndash; Marc Rogers and Kevin
Mahaffey</a>. Tesla did an amazing job of securing their
vehicle&mdash;especially considering how connected it is.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#AmmonRa">How to hack your way out of home detention &ndash;
AmmonRa</a>. Neat idea. Fake the messages from your
ankle bracelet while you cloak your existing one with a Faraday cage. You could get someone else in trouble by making
them appear outside their confinement zone too.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#L%C3%B8ge">Tell me who you are and I will tell you your lock pattern &ndash; Marte
Løge</a>. Turns out, people are predictable. And lock codes
maybe aren&rsquo;t all that secure.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Rock">I Will Kill You &ndash; Chris Rock</a>. <em>My favorite talk at
DEFCON 23.</em> Our birth and death record-keeping needs some modernization.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Sandvik">When IoT attacks: hacking a Linux-powered rifle &ndash; Runa A. Sandvik &amp; Michael
Auger</a>. Sad to see an Austin-based company taken
down, but come on&mdash;an internet-enabled rifle? you knew this was coming.</p>

<h2>Saturday</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#McGrew">I Hunt Penetration Testers: More Weaknesses in Tools and Procedures &ndash; Wesley
McGrew</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Shoshitaishvili">Angry Hacking &ndash; the next generation of binary analysis &ndash; Yan Shoshitaishvili &amp; Fish
Wang</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Miller">Remote exploitation of an unaltered passenger vehicle &ndash; Charlie Miller and Chris
Valasek</a>. Dr. Miller and Chris Valasek are always
entertaining. Their presentation style is unlike any others&mdash;they either rehearse a ton or they have great chemistry and
complementary personalities. This continued their work hacking Jeeps. At the time of the talk, their exploits had been
fixed so all is well&hellip; for now.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Ryan">Hacking Electric Skateboards: Vehicle Research For Mortals &ndash; Mike Ryan &amp; Richo
Healey</a>. The timing on this was awesome! This came right
after the &ldquo;hack a Jeep&rdquo; talk and the humility of the presenters (&ldquo;vehicle research for mortals&rdquo;) was great. Basically,
if you build an internet- or bluetooth-enabled device, you will get hacked.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Kaminsky">I  want these * bugs off my * Internet &ndash; Dan
Kaminsky</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Talabis">The Bieber Project: Ad Tech 101, Fake Fans and Adventures in Buying Internet Traffic &ndash; Mark Ryan
Talabis</a>. Online ads baffle me. I think it is really
hard to connect ads to revenue, with an underlying belief that ads are not a wise use of capital. The presenter showed a
Chinese ad fraud system called jingling that spawns a ton of threads and programmatically clicks links; while running
jingling you accumulate tokens that you spend to get others to click on your links. Some people claim to make an extra
$50/day (or far more) just by participating. Brilliant!</p>

<h2>Sunday</h2>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Domas">REpsych: Psychological Warfare in Reverse Engineering &ndash; Chris
Domas</a>. I missed the first half, but what I gathered is
that Chris Domas was able to figure out how to create binaries that form images when viewed in a disassembler like IDA.
He showed a silly malware that dynamically found images on your computer and made binaries that match the images&mdash;he
joked that he would stop probing any malware that could present his portrait.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Wardle2">Stick That In Your (root)Pipe &amp; Smoke It &ndash; Patrick
Wardle</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Coskun">Why nation-state malwares target Telco Networks: Dissecting technical capabilities of Regin and its counterparts &ndash; Omer
Coskun</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Lawshae">Let&rsquo;s Talk About SOAP, Baby. Let&rsquo;s Talk About UPNP &ndash; Ricky &ldquo;HeadlessZeke&rdquo;
Lawshae</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read March 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-march-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-march-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple long books this month.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015DPXKI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015DPXKI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Anathem by Neal
Stephenson</a>.
Hmm. I love Neal Stephenson&mdash;Diamond Age is one of my favorite books
ever&mdash;but this book didn&rsquo;t do it for me. I didn&rsquo;t get it. It was
intelligent and well researched&mdash;it just wasn&rsquo;t for me.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">The Well of Ascension by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
Book Two of the Mistborn trilogy. It started slowly, but ended well. Let
me expand on that a bit: the first book&mdash;to me&mdash;was about a rebellion in
a novel low-magic world. The second book has to pick up the pieces of
that rebellion, so it&rsquo;s more about government and interpersonal
conflicts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/sxsw-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/sxsw-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed myself a lot at SXSW 2015. I made it to a lot of sessions that were interesting and thought-provoking.</p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li>Welcome to SXSW Interactive by Hugh Forest</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997613">The Climate Crisis: Challenge and Opportunity by Al Gore</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996684">How to Rock SXSW in 4 Hours by Tim Ferriss</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42182">Fear, Shame, Empathy, &amp; More Ways to Change Behavior by Dan Pink</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40327">Building Gender-Balanced Startups (Panel) by Sarah Buhr, Julie Ann Horvath, Stewart Alsop, Vanessa Camones</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39145">OAuth2: The Swiss-Army Framework by Brent Shaffer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP41723">Patagonia: Why Business Is Good for the Planet by Rose Marcario</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42485">UFC: Women Breaking Ground Inside the Octagon (Panel) by Dana White, Ronda Rousey, Jessica Eye</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996358">Princess Reema&rsquo;s Mission to Empower Saudi Women by Princess Reema</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43837">What it Really Takes to Win in Business by Jack Welch and Gary Vaynerchuk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP37185">Beyond Privacy: Surveillance&rsquo;s Threat To Liberty by Schneier and Wizner</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Sunday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39695">Transgender in Tech: Past, Present, Future (Panel) by Allyson Dylan Robinson, Brielle Harrison, Kortney Ziegler, and Meghan Stabler</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43232">Be Epic: The Art of Bold Decision Making by Phil Libin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996157">AI, Immortality and the Future of Selves by Martine Rothblatt</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36963">Data (in)Security: MIT Scientists Tackle Privacy (Panel) by Danny Weitzner, Ronald Rivest, Sam Madden</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43378">How to Fix American Politics by David Burstein</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Monday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43236">The Frontiers of Computational Thinking by Stephen Wolfram</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43059">Everything Eric Ries Has Learned Since 2011 by Eric Ries</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996700">Fixing Transportation with Humanity and Technology by Logan Green</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996698">Lessons from BuzzFeed by Jonah Peretti</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996699">Bitcoin: What It Needs to Succeed (Panel) by the Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tuesday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40699">Accelerators by the Numbers: 2014 Rankings by Susan Cohen and Yael Hochberg</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996685">Better and Faster: Predict Opportunity &amp; Win in 2015 by Jeremy Grutsche</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997484">Holacracy: A Radical New Approach to Management by Brian Robertson</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996703">Moonshots and Reality by Astro Teller</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36218">How to Rob a Bank: Vulnerabilities of New Money by Josh Alexander, Bo Hartman, Bob Blakely</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read February 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-february-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-february-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One really long book dominated my reading this this month&mdash;I only
finished two books, but they were both very good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009JNXC36/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009JNXC36&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre
Dumas</a>.
This book is a classic for a reason. I prefer modern books, but I
decided to give Count of Monte Cristo a try, and I&rsquo;m glad I did.
The story was really good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DYXC3W8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DYXC3W8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Warbound by Larry
Correia</a>.
I&rsquo;m really enjoying Larry Correia. He has the adventure fantasy story down. His
novels are fun and well-paced with memorable characters, and they feel
like the right amount of story per book. Warbound
concludes the Grimnoir Chronicles, providing a fitting finish.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read January 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-january-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-january-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">Mistborn by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
A solid fantasty novel with an interesting magic system. In Mistborn, a
select few people are gifted with the ability to burn a metal internally
granting them abilities like improved strength or improved hearing. The
elevated ability lasts as long as the metal remains with the metal
burning in proportion to the power you demand of it. An even smaller
group can burn all metals. I liked it a lot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/art-of-conflict-management-achieving-solutions-for-life-work-and-beyond.html">The Art of Conflict Management by Michael
Dues</a>.
I now think that conflict management is the most important skill a
person can have. I wish this stuff was taught in school! It was very
helpful for me to learn the basics, which provided me with a framework
for understanding conflict (&ldquo;discomforting differences&rdquo;).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AFPVOTG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AFPVOTG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=JWTMJY6TXCVPZDCO">Finding Your Element by Sir Ken
Robinson</a>. Ken Robinson had a great
tech talk, so I thought I&rsquo;d like the book. It was good, but not really
what I need. I&rsquo;d recommend the book to young people who are floundering as they embark on
adulthood or middle-aged people struggling to understand where they fit
into the scheme of things.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C438CW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004C438CW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=7XHAOVDX33VKT7OV">No More Mr. Nice Guy by Robert
Glover</a>. I don&rsquo;t know how to feel about this book. I think it has a lot of really good information for nice guys who are unfulfilled; however, it raises some questions regarding masculinity and being kind but firm. Some of the positive points: men should spend time with other men, people should stand up for themselves and they should get what they want, and couples should evenly divide work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
