<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-22T14:13:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Checklist for Success]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/daily-rituals-for-success/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/daily-rituals-for-success</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Personal rituals are fascinating to me. I&rsquo;ve encountered them repeatedly in books, blogs, podcasts, and conversations. They&rsquo;re generally boiled down to 1-60 minute morning rituals, but I chafe at the idea of an immutable hour-long routine because I have at least four different types of days (calm weekday, rushed weekday, calm weekend, and rushed weekend). It&rsquo;s easier for me to think of the idealized morning routine as a daily checklist that I can achieve in whatever order during any waking period.</p>

<p>This year I&rsquo;ve focused a lot on my own health and happiness, paying special attention to what drains me of <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7LnBvuzjpr4">my energy</a>. Through reading and experimenting I&rsquo;ve come up with my own checklist. These are the things that I shoot for every day (in no particular order):</p>

<ul>
<li>smile for one minute &ndash; Smiling feels good, and there&rsquo;s always something worth smiling about. But I rarely smile. I&rsquo;m generally happy, but I tend to suppress the physical representation of my emotions so I don&rsquo;t smile nearly as much as I&rsquo;d like to. I&rsquo;m working on making my outside match my inside more often.</li>
<li>journal 3+ things I&rsquo;m grateful for &ndash; I try to smile while thinking of things I&rsquo;m grateful for. It would be easy enough to say, &ldquo;my wife&rdquo;, &ldquo;my health&rdquo;, and &ldquo;my job&rdquo;, but I try to get more specific. Practicing gratitude has been very helpful for me.</li>
<li>journal anything I&rsquo;m proud of myself for &ndash; I struggle with self-confidence and self-compassion, so this running log of goodness helps me feel better.</li>
<li>breathe from the diagram, trying to take only 4-6 breaths in one minute &ndash; It&rsquo;s amazing how calm I feel after slowing my breathing&mdash;it&rsquo;s like telling your body, &ldquo;relax&rdquo; and having your body listen.</li>
<li>sleep 7.5+ hours &ndash; Sleep is generally the first thing to go when I get busy; however, I&rsquo;m finding that sleep really sets the stage for the day, so I&rsquo;m trying to sleep more.</li>
<li>stand 2+ hours &ndash; On my laziest day I could stand for less than five minutes, which is bad for my mood and my metabolism. I installed a flip-up table so I can work standing up. I&rsquo;m trying to stand once an hour (drinking a lot of water helps motivate me). I&rsquo;ve also been doing a lot of housework recently, so I&rsquo;m standing more.</li>
<li>walk at least 3,000 steps &ndash; You know that laziest day where I hardly stand? I definitely don&rsquo;t walk much those days. For reference 3,000 steps is roughly 1.5 miles and 30 minutes moving around. Since I made 3,000 steps a goal I&rsquo;ve been able to do it almost every day.</li>
<li>exercise until sweating &ndash; Typical exercise guidelines recommend around five hours of exercise per week, but most Americans are barely getting two hours, so I try to be realistic. I think &ldquo;until sweating&rdquo; is a better goal than any specific time. Get the blood moving and enjoy.</li>
<li>have sex &ndash; I never see this in people&rsquo;s daily routines, but I think it&rsquo;s very important so I had to include it. That said, this is probably my most skipped routine.</li>
<li>get some physical contact with loved ones (including pets) &ndash; Positive physical contact releases oxytocin, which makes us feel connected and warm. Blood pressure drops and we feel a sense of well-being. Pretty powerful stuff. I&rsquo;ve read various studies saying it takes from one second to two minutes, so I shoot for one good purposeful spouse-hug and a minute of cuddling with the pets.</li>
<li>take a probiotic &ndash; Get your shit straight. For real.</li>
<li>eat some fiber &ndash; See above.</li>
<li>fill in vitamins and minerals you have missed or will miss from your food and drink &ndash; I generally eat well for 3/5 feedings (traditional meals plus snacks), but I still miss a lot of nutrients. Vitamin D, which is usually provided by exposure to the sun, is chronically low among programmers. If I can&rsquo;t go for a little walk in the sun then I take my vitamin D.</li>
<li>drink 64+ oz of water &ndash; Studies refute the biological need for 8 cups of water, but I&rsquo;ve found that it&rsquo;s fairly easy and it makes me feel better.</li>
<li>brush your teeth twice &ndash; Your mother will be proud.</li>
<li>make your bed &ndash; For me, this helps set the stage for a productive day. I don&rsquo;t do anything fancy&mdash;just straighten the sheets and comforter and pull them up over my pillows.</li>
<li>stretch &ndash; My flexibility sucks. I think some of my body aches come from poor flexibility, so I&rsquo;m working to improve my general mobility.</li>
<li>communicate with someone important to me (preferably someone that I don&rsquo;t work or live with) &ndash; Relationships mean a lot to me, yet I&rsquo;m historically bad at keeping in touch. While far from perfect now, by focusing on it every day I&rsquo;ve been able to keep up with more loved ones.</li>
<li>meditate &ndash; I try to meditate every day, but &ldquo;meditation&rdquo; is a really open-ended idea. I&rsquo;ve found success in short mindfulness breaks. Focusing on breathing from my diaphragm, clearing my mind with intense exercise, and recognizing the blessings around me all achieve a similar effect for me.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you&rsquo;re on the fence about any item, run the experiment and see how you feel after trying it.</p>

<p>So, what&rsquo;s your daily checklist? What works for you? What percentage of your tasks do you normally complete?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DEFCON 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/defcon-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/defcon-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>DEFCON 23 was my favorite DEFCON experience so far. There were a lot of great talks and fun after-hours events. Below is
a list of talks that I attended, for posterity&rsquo;s sake.</p>

<h2>Thursday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Reed">Hardware and Trust Security: Explain it like I’m 5 &ndash; Teddy Reed and Nick
Anderson</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Szakaly">Shall We Play a Game? &ndash; Tamas Szakaly</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Drake">Stagefright: Scary Code in the Heart of Android &ndash; Joshua J.
Drake</a>. This talk explained the Android exploits that
arise because Android pre-processes incoming messages. For example, texting a malicious image leads Android to retrieve
and load the payload before the user even sees a notification. This should make the user interface feel faster, but it
comes at a price.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Schneier">Bruce Schneier Q&amp;A &ndash; Bruce Schneier</a>. I &lt;3 Bruce.
He&rsquo;s just so clear and intelligent. I hope we make him head of cyber security for the U.S.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Kamkar">Drive It Like You Hacked It: New Attacks and Tools to Wirelessly Steal Cars &ndash; Samy
Kamkar</a>. Samy is one of my favorite security
researchers&mdash;I highly recommend his talks. This talk was funny and informative.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Rogers">How to Hack a Tesla Model S &ndash; Marc Rogers and Kevin
Mahaffey</a>. Tesla did an amazing job of securing their
vehicle&mdash;especially considering how connected it is.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#AmmonRa">How to hack your way out of home detention &ndash;
AmmonRa</a>. Neat idea. Fake the messages from your
ankle bracelet while you cloak your existing one with a Faraday cage. You could get someone else in trouble by making
them appear outside their confinement zone too.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#L%C3%B8ge">Tell me who you are and I will tell you your lock pattern &ndash; Marte
Løge</a>. Turns out, people are predictable. And lock codes
maybe aren&rsquo;t all that secure.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Rock">I Will Kill You &ndash; Chris Rock</a>. <em>My favorite talk at
DEFCON 23.</em> Our birth and death record-keeping needs some modernization.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Sandvik">When IoT attacks: hacking a Linux-powered rifle &ndash; Runa A. Sandvik &amp; Michael
Auger</a>. Sad to see an Austin-based company taken
down, but come on&mdash;an internet-enabled rifle? you knew this was coming.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#McGrew">I Hunt Penetration Testers: More Weaknesses in Tools and Procedures &ndash; Wesley
McGrew</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Shoshitaishvili">Angry Hacking &ndash; the next generation of binary analysis &ndash; Yan Shoshitaishvili &amp; Fish
Wang</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Miller">Remote exploitation of an unaltered passenger vehicle &ndash; Charlie Miller and Chris
Valasek</a>. Dr. Miller and Chris Valasek are always
entertaining. Their presentation style is unlike any others&mdash;they either rehearse a ton or they have great chemistry and
complementary personalities. This continued their work hacking Jeeps. At the time of the talk, their exploits had been
fixed so all is well&hellip; for now.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Ryan">Hacking Electric Skateboards: Vehicle Research For Mortals &ndash; Mike Ryan &amp; Richo
Healey</a>. The timing on this was awesome! This came right
after the &ldquo;hack a Jeep&rdquo; talk and the humility of the presenters (&ldquo;vehicle research for mortals&rdquo;) was great. Basically,
if you build an internet- or bluetooth-enabled device, you will get hacked.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Kaminsky">I  want these * bugs off my * Internet &ndash; Dan
Kaminsky</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Talabis">The Bieber Project: Ad Tech 101, Fake Fans and Adventures in Buying Internet Traffic &ndash; Mark Ryan
Talabis</a>. Online ads baffle me. I think it is really
hard to connect ads to revenue, with an underlying belief that ads are not a wise use of capital. The presenter showed a
Chinese ad fraud system called jingling that spawns a ton of threads and programmatically clicks links; while running
jingling you accumulate tokens that you spend to get others to click on your links. Some people claim to make an extra
$50/day (or far more) just by participating. Brilliant!</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Sunday</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Domas">REpsych: Psychological Warfare in Reverse Engineering &ndash; Chris
Domas</a>. I missed the first half, but what I gathered is
that Chris Domas was able to figure out how to create binaries that form images when viewed in a disassembler like IDA.
He showed a silly malware that dynamically found images on your computer and made binaries that match the images&mdash;he
joked that he would stop probing any malware that could present his portrait.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Wardle2">Stick That In Your (root)Pipe &amp; Smoke It &ndash; Patrick
Wardle</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Coskun">Why nation-state malwares target Telco Networks: Dissecting technical capabilities of Regin and its counterparts &ndash; Omer
Coskun</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-23/dc-23-speakers.html#Lawshae">Let&rsquo;s Talk About SOAP, Baby. Let&rsquo;s Talk About UPNP &ndash; Ricky &ldquo;HeadlessZeke&rdquo;
Lawshae</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read March 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-march-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-march-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple long books this month.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015DPXKI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015DPXKI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Anathem by Neal
Stephenson</a>.
Hmm. I love Neal Stephenson&mdash;Diamond Age is one of my favorite books
ever&mdash;but this book didn&rsquo;t do it for me. I didn&rsquo;t get it. It was
intelligent and well researched&mdash;it just wasn&rsquo;t for me.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">The Well of Ascension by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
Book Two of the Mistborn trilogy. It started slowly, but ended well. Let
me expand on that a bit: the first book&mdash;to me&mdash;was about a rebellion in
a novel low-magic world. The second book has to pick up the pieces of
that rebellion, so it&rsquo;s more about government and interpersonal
conflicts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/sxsw-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/sxsw-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed myself a lot at SXSW 2015. I made it to a lot of sessions that were interesting and thought-provoking.</p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li>Welcome to SXSW Interactive by Hugh Forest</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997613">The Climate Crisis: Challenge and Opportunity by Al Gore</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996684">How to Rock SXSW in 4 Hours by Tim Ferriss</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42182">Fear, Shame, Empathy, &amp; More Ways to Change Behavior by Dan Pink</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40327">Building Gender-Balanced Startups (Panel) by Sarah Buhr, Julie Ann Horvath, Stewart Alsop, Vanessa Camones</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39145">OAuth2: The Swiss-Army Framework by Brent Shaffer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP41723">Patagonia: Why Business Is Good for the Planet by Rose Marcario</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42485">UFC: Women Breaking Ground Inside the Octagon (Panel) by Dana White, Ronda Rousey, Jessica Eye</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996358">Princess Reema&rsquo;s Mission to Empower Saudi Women by Princess Reema</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43837">What it Really Takes to Win in Business by Jack Welch and Gary Vaynerchuk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP37185">Beyond Privacy: Surveillance&rsquo;s Threat To Liberty by Schneier and Wizner</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Sunday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39695">Transgender in Tech: Past, Present, Future (Panel) by Allyson Dylan Robinson, Brielle Harrison, Kortney Ziegler, and Meghan Stabler</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43232">Be Epic: The Art of Bold Decision Making by Phil Libin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996157">AI, Immortality and the Future of Selves by Martine Rothblatt</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36963">Data (in)Security: MIT Scientists Tackle Privacy (Panel) by Danny Weitzner, Ronald Rivest, Sam Madden</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43378">How to Fix American Politics by David Burstein</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Monday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43236">The Frontiers of Computational Thinking by Stephen Wolfram</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43059">Everything Eric Ries Has Learned Since 2011 by Eric Ries</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996700">Fixing Transportation with Humanity and Technology by Logan Green</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996698">Lessons from BuzzFeed by Jonah Peretti</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996699">Bitcoin: What It Needs to Succeed (Panel) by the Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tuesday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40699">Accelerators by the Numbers: 2014 Rankings by Susan Cohen and Yael Hochberg</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996685">Better and Faster: Predict Opportunity &amp; Win in 2015 by Jeremy Grutsche</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997484">Holacracy: A Radical New Approach to Management by Brian Robertson</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996703">Moonshots and Reality by Astro Teller</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36218">How to Rob a Bank: Vulnerabilities of New Money by Josh Alexander, Bo Hartman, Bob Blakely</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read February 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-february-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/books-read-february-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One really long book dominated my reading this this month&mdash;I only
finished two books, but they were both very good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009JNXC36/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009JNXC36&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre
Dumas</a>.
This book is a classic for a reason. I prefer modern books, but I
decided to give Count of Monte Cristo a try, and I&rsquo;m glad I did.
The story was really good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DYXC3W8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DYXC3W8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Warbound by Larry
Correia</a>.
I&rsquo;m really enjoying Larry Correia. He has the adventure fantasy story down. His
novels are fun and well-paced with memorable characters, and they feel
like the right amount of story per book. Warbound
concludes the Grimnoir Chronicles, providing a fitting finish.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
