<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-15T20:09:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//github/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read March 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-march-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-march-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A couple long books this month.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0015DPXKI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0015DPXKI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Anathem by Neal
Stephenson</a>.
Hmm. I love Neal Stephenson&mdash;Diamond Age is one of my favorite books
ever&mdash;but this book didn&rsquo;t do it for me. I didn&rsquo;t get it. It was
intelligent and well researched&mdash;it just wasn&rsquo;t for me.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">The Well of Ascension by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
Book Two of the Mistborn trilogy. It started slowly, but ended well. Let
me expand on that a bit: the first book&mdash;to me&mdash;was about a rebellion in
a novel low-magic world. The second book has to pick up the pieces of
that rebellion, so it&rsquo;s more about government and interpersonal
conflicts.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW 2015 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/sxsw-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//github/sxsw-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoyed myself a lot at SXSW 2015. I made it to a lot of sessions that were interesting and thought-provoking.</p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li>Welcome to SXSW Interactive by Hugh Forest</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997613">The Climate Crisis: Challenge and Opportunity by Al Gore</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996684">How to Rock SXSW in 4 Hours by Tim Ferriss</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42182">Fear, Shame, Empathy, &amp; More Ways to Change Behavior by Dan Pink</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40327">Building Gender-Balanced Startups (Panel) by Sarah Buhr, Julie Ann Horvath, Stewart Alsop, Vanessa Camones</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39145">OAuth2: The Swiss-Army Framework by Brent Shaffer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP41723">Patagonia: Why Business Is Good for the Planet by Rose Marcario</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP42485">UFC: Women Breaking Ground Inside the Octagon (Panel) by Dana White, Ronda Rousey, Jessica Eye</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996358">Princess Reema&rsquo;s Mission to Empower Saudi Women by Princess Reema</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43837">What it Really Takes to Win in Business by Jack Welch and Gary Vaynerchuk</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP37185">Beyond Privacy: Surveillance&rsquo;s Threat To Liberty by Schneier and Wizner</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Sunday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP39695">Transgender in Tech: Past, Present, Future (Panel) by Allyson Dylan Robinson, Brielle Harrison, Kortney Ziegler, and Meghan Stabler</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43232">Be Epic: The Art of Bold Decision Making by Phil Libin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996157">AI, Immortality and the Future of Selves by Martine Rothblatt</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36963">Data (in)Security: MIT Scientists Tackle Privacy (Panel) by Danny Weitzner, Ronald Rivest, Sam Madden</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43378">How to Fix American Politics by David Burstein</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Monday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43236">The Frontiers of Computational Thinking by Stephen Wolfram</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP43059">Everything Eric Ries Has Learned Since 2011 by Eric Ries</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996700">Fixing Transportation with Humanity and Technology by Logan Green</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996698">Lessons from BuzzFeed by Jonah Peretti</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996699">Bitcoin: What It Needs to Succeed (Panel) by the Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tuesday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP40699">Accelerators by the Numbers: 2014 Rankings by Susan Cohen and Yael Hochberg</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996685">Better and Faster: Predict Opportunity &amp; Win in 2015 by Jeremy Grutsche</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP997484">Holacracy: A Radical New Approach to Management by Brian Robertson</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP996703">Moonshots and Reality by Astro Teller</a></li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2015/events/event_IAP36218">How to Rob a Bank: Vulnerabilities of New Money by Josh Alexander, Bo Hartman, Bob Blakely</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read February 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-february-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-february-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One really long book dominated my reading this this month&mdash;I only
finished two books, but they were both very good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009JNXC36/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009JNXC36&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Count of Monte Cristo by Alexandre
Dumas</a>.
This book is a classic for a reason. I prefer modern books, but I
decided to give Count of Monte Cristo a try, and I&rsquo;m glad I did.
The story was really good.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DYXC3W8/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00DYXC3W8&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Warbound by Larry
Correia</a>.
I&rsquo;m really enjoying Larry Correia. He has the adventure fantasy story down. His
novels are fun and well-paced with memorable characters, and they feel
like the right amount of story per book. Warbound
concludes the Grimnoir Chronicles, providing a fitting finish.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read January 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-january-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-january-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">Mistborn by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
A solid fantasty novel with an interesting magic system. In Mistborn, a
select few people are gifted with the ability to burn a metal internally
granting them abilities like improved strength or improved hearing. The
elevated ability lasts as long as the metal remains with the metal
burning in proportion to the power you demand of it. An even smaller
group can burn all metals. I liked it a lot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/art-of-conflict-management-achieving-solutions-for-life-work-and-beyond.html">The Art of Conflict Management by Michael
Dues</a>.
I now think that conflict management is the most important skill a
person can have. I wish this stuff was taught in school! It was very
helpful for me to learn the basics, which provided me with a framework
for understanding conflict (&ldquo;discomforting differences&rdquo;).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AFPVOTG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AFPVOTG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=JWTMJY6TXCVPZDCO">Finding Your Element by Sir Ken
Robinson</a>. Ken Robinson had a great
tech talk, so I thought I&rsquo;d like the book. It was good, but not really
what I need. I&rsquo;d recommend the book to young people who are floundering as they embark on
adulthood or middle-aged people struggling to understand where they fit
into the scheme of things.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C438CW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004C438CW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=7XHAOVDX33VKT7OV">No More Mr. Nice Guy by Robert
Glover</a>. I don&rsquo;t know how to feel about this book. I think it has a lot of really good information for nice guys who are unfulfilled; however, it raises some questions regarding masculinity and being kind but firm. Some of the positive points: men should spend time with other men, people should stand up for themselves and they should get what they want, and couples should evenly divide work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read December 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-december-2014/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//github/books-read-december-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a busy month for reading. Lots of good stuff!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00ARSJNW6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00ARSJNW6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KQP7U6OB4WMDL2XX">Dracula Chronicles: Son of the Dragon by Victor
Foia</a>. An interesting retelling of the life of Dracula. This book, the first of three, tracks Dracula in his teenage years as he makes his first kill. The book was really good, but I was looking for more fantasy.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00APA1NK6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00APA1NK6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=WMOFDYAVZR4UFKHT">Spellbound by Larry
Correia</a>. Correia has the fantasy adventure
story down. Very entertaining. I look forward to finishing the series
(Grimnoir Chronicles) soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CD360ZQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00CD360ZQ&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KKUCVAWJ3O2JOMPV">Alas, Babylon by Pat
Frank</a>. A slice of life in the alternate reality
where the cold war ended with nuclear war. I could see this
book as the precursor to The Road by McCarthy. I liked it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D4CBA50/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00D4CBA50&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KN3MMS2ERWTKFAU7">At the Mountains of Madness by H.P.
Lovecraft</a>. Beware the elder
things buried in Antarctica.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00COOFBA4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00COOFBA4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=U74HXIB7CQ3OEZNU">How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big by Scott
Adams</a>. Scott Adams is the creator of the workplace comic, <a href="http://www.dilbert.com/">Dilbert</a>. In this book Adams lays out his lessons on life. Some of the high points: eat well, exercise, get into a routine, optimize your personal energy, learn as many different skills as you can (because success is likely to come from some combination of your skills), and passion is just a fancy way for successful people to say they got lucky. I really liked the book; I thought it was funny and informative, and I loved the humility with which the story was told. Where many books and life stories rewrite history and show how one success begot another, Adams instead talks about how his failures lead to success. The anecdotes were modest and on-point, which I found refreshing and brave.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009U9S6FI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009U9S6FI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3S6RUEUONCG3UEAU">Man&rsquo;s Search for Meaning by Viktor
Frankl</a>. A Jewish psychiatrist&rsquo;s
Holocaust story helps explain his world view and motivate his
psychotherapy approach,
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy">Logotherapy</a>. I appreciated
that the book was honest without dwelling too much on the atrocities:
rather than recounting every terrible thing that happened, Frankl picks
a few key events that provide a broad understanding. Remarkably, Frankl
does something constructive with his grief. In the book he mentions that
Logotherapy might ask a patient why that patient does not commit
suicide because the answer reveals your meaning, which you can then work
with to heal. One of the most disturbing parts of the book for me was
Frankl&rsquo;s account of returning home to a nation that ignored the
concentration camps or downplayed their significance; he writes that for
many survivors life after the camp was harder than life in the camp.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009AYWPCI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009AYWPCI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=XSJDV3OEBODUC5IH">Futures and Frosting by Tara
Sivec</a>. Futures and Frosting tells the
story of how a single-mother is reunited with the father of her child;
after a lot of confusion, the couple gets married and has another kid,
then lives happily ever after. Without the humor, it would read like
an angsty young adult love story.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596518382/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596518382&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=HYDQVVVHWRDD54ZB">Apprenticeship Patterns by Dave Hoover and Ade
Oshineye</a>.
This was probably the most accessible technical book I&rsquo;ve read. The
application of pattern language to a career is really clever and worked
well. As with software patterns, it&rsquo;s nice to see the path.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
