<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-16T09:52:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favoriate Reads of 2018]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2018/"/>
    <updated>2018-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2018</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/10936110">reads from 2018</a>. In 2018 my reading focused a lot on improving myself in order to make me a better husband, father, manager, and all-around person.</p>




<p>Over the years I’ve read a lot about management, however, a lot of it is very high level. I read and enjoyed <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/https://www.radicalcandor.com/">Radical Candor</a> by Kim Scott because it provided an opinionated overview of how to manage like when and how to have career conversations. I found a lot of the suggestions helpful as I officially began my management career.</p>




<p>I finished the available <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Years_of_Lyndon_Johnson">LBJ biographies by Robert A. Caro</a>, which I highly recommend. Between those and <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dictator%27s_Handbook">The Dictator’s Handbook: Why Bad Behavior is Almost Always Good Politics</a> by Bruce Bueno de Mesquita I had a new framework for interpreting today’s political landscape.</p>




<p>On the non-fiction front, I read and enjoyed the <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://nnedi.com/books/binti.html">Binti</a> series and the <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/https://www.goodreads.com/series/192752-bobiverse">Bobiverse</a> series. Both were quick, thought-provoking sci-fi series.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favoriate Reads of 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite reads from 2017.</p>




<h3>Fiction</h3>




<ul>
<li><a href="">Reamde</a> by Neal Stephenson – I have enjoyed every Neal Stephenson book I’ve read, and this is no exception. I’ve played a lot of online games over the years, so this book hooked me by starting off with a computer virus spread in an online game. It develops nicely from there.</li>
<li><a href="">The Moon is a Harsh Mistress</a> by Robert Heinlein – Truly ahead of its time. This book felt modern with its space travel and artificial intelligence, but it was written in the 1950s!</li>
<li><a href="">Ancillary Justice</a> by Leckie – This book has won a ton of awards so it is not too surprising that it is good. It has some really interesting ideas with AI and consciousness.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Series</h3>




<ul>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds</a> by Drew Hayes – College kids with super powers. That’s a hell of a mashup. I found the three published books very entertaining. The characters were interesting, the scenarios were realistic, and the magic system was well thought out and balanced (which is not easy to do with super powers).</li>
</ul>




<h3>Non-fiction</h3>




<ul>
<li><a href="">The Path To Power</a> and <a href="">Means of Ascent</a> by Robert Caro – These are the first two books in a long biography series about LBJ, one of America’s most interesting presidents. Ryan Holiday recommended these and I see why. Amazing character and great writing make these books easy to read. It helped me feel better about today’s political climate.</li>
<li><a href="">Ideal Team Player</a> by Lencioni – Lencioni has carved out a niche with his leadership fables—basically, business books wrapped in a narrative. I’ve read most of his books now and they fit together really nicely. I want to be an ideal team player and this book gave me food for thought.</li>
<li><a href="">Anatomy of Peace</a> by The Arbinger Institute – Another business book wrapped in a narrative. Peace is a great goal, so I was glad to learn more about how we can all overcome conflict and find peace.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favoriate Reads of 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite reads from 2016.</p>




<h3>Fiction</h3>




<ul>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/1RX9aIm">Lord of All Things</a> by Andreas Eschbach – This book had a lot of new-to-me ideas and the sci-fi was integrated nicely into a story I enjoyed. One of the things that stands out is that tradeoffs exist with every choice.</li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/2ixJgRY">Seveneves</a> by Neal Stephenson – Amazing concepts that my mind keeps turning over. I love Neal Stephenson and this is yet another mind-expanding novel from him. This book really hit him as Elon Musk started speaking more publicly about getting off Earth.</li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/2in6xFW">Stories of Your Life and Others</a> by Ted Chiang – I don’t tend to read many short stories, but I’m glad I read this collection. About half the stories were really good and still have me thinking.</li>
</ul>




<h4>Series</h4>




<ul>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/1YefYmk">Red Rising by Pierce Brown</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/1UHiSBW">Riyria Chronicles by Michael J. Sullivan</a></li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/2iWcyur">Lightbringer series by Brent Weeks</a></li>
</ul>




<h3>Non-fiction</h3>




<ul>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/294eAPo">Them: Adventures with Extremists</a> by Jon Ronson – A great story in the midst of a very extreme 2016.</li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/2hHFvrV">Surely You’re Joking, Mr. Feynman!: Adventures of a Curious Character</a> by Richard Feynman – This is my new standard for an autobiography. Entertaining and interesting throughout, with great insights into this curious character. I particularly liked that he didn’t want more money because it would allow him to afford mistress, which he knew would ruin his life.</li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/2iUcmre">Home Game: An Accidental Guide to Fatherhood</a> by Michael Lewis – I would recommend this to any new father. It’s short and funny with Michael Lewis plainly saying so many things I had thought. I’ve used his question “what percentage of the parenting does each parent do?” several times now. He says that fathers do much less than mothers but there’s a lot of social stigma to admitting that, which made me feel better.</li>
<li><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://amzn.to/2in8Et5">When Things Fall Apart: Heart Advice for Difficult Times</a> by Pema Chodron – This book dovetailed nicely with my efforts to control my emotions. I read no more than one chapter at a time because it’s heavy, introspective stuff. I was thrilled that I read this beeok when I saw Derek Sivers mention Pema Chodron in his <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://nownownow.com/about">about now pages post</a>.</li>
</ul>




<p>That’s my not-so-short list of favorites from 2016. I hope 2017 will be filled with as many great stories.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Favoriate Reads of 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/favorite-reads-in-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Different books give me different things, so it’s hard to rank them. But here are a few books that stand out from this year’s reading list.</p>




<ul>
<li><p>The Stormlight Archive books 1 and 2 by Brandon Sanderson: <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Way-Kings-Stormlight-Archive-Book-ebook/dp/B003P2WO5E/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818313&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Way of Kings</a> and <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Words-Radiance-Stormlight-Archive-Book-ebook/dp/B00DA6YEKS/ref=sr_1_2?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818313&amp;sr=1-2&amp;tag=theven01-20">Words of Radiance</a>. I read seven Brandon Sanderson books in 2015, so it’s fair to say I enjoy his writing. This is set to be a 10-book epic fantasy series in the vein of <em>The Wheel of Time</em>, which Sanderson finished with aplomb. I hate having to wait so long to reach the conclusion, but I’m prepared to do so because the first two were so good.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Trust-Me-Lying-Confessions-Manipulator-ebook/dp/B0074VTHH0/?tag=theven01-20">Trust Me, I’m Lying by Ryan Holiday</a>. The media is bullshit—read this book if you don’t believe me. Ryan Holiday talks candidly about the tricks he and so many others use to generate traffic.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/So-Youve-Been-Publicly-Shamed-ebook/dp/B00L9B7IRC/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818288&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">So You’ve Been Publicly Shamed by Jon Ronson</a>. Between this and <em>Trust Me, I’m Lying</em> I was really sad about the state of media and the rise of outrage porn. Real lives are ruined and only the media wins.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Art-Asking-Learned-Worrying-People-ebook/dp/B00IRISKD6/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818262&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Art of Asking by Amanda Palmer</a>. Another book with ties to shame and acceptance. Amanda Palmer has a confessional style that is really disarming. People have been really mean to her, so her message of love and empathy is that much more amazing.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Radical-Acceptance-Tara-Brach-ebook/dp/B000FC2NHG/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450818241&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">Radical Acceptance by Tara Brach</a>. A breath of fresh air among the negativity in some of my other notable reads from the year. Reading this book made me feel better about myself.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Contagious-Things-Catch-Jonah-Berger-ebook/dp/B008J4GQKW/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817798&amp;tag=theven01-20">Contagious by Jonah Berger</a>. Contagious sheds light on why some things are shared and others aren’t, which was particularly interesting in the context of shame and media manipulation.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Things-Shout-Out-Loud-Parties-ebook/dp/B00L2FG1SM/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817769&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">Things to shout out loud at parties. by Markus Almond</a>. I love the style of this book. It’s a collection of no-more-than-one-page stories and thoughts so it’s very approachable. I think everyone should aim to write a similar book.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Jesus-Son-Stories-Denis-Johnson-ebook/dp/B006JR7XLC/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817738&amp;tag=theven01-20">Jesus’ Son by Denis Johnson</a>. Another book with a unique style. This one is a collection of stories about a junkie stumbling through life where the writing is as stark and jumpy as you’d expect from a junkie.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Becoming-Technical-Leader-Gerald-Weinberg-ebook/dp/B004J4VV3I/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1450817692&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">Becoming a Technical Leader by Gerald Weinberg</a>. This book is unlike any other ‘how to be a leader’ book that I’ve read. It’s full of great ideas like, ‘maybe poor personal hygiene is about poor self-confidence so be mindful when offering advice’ and Satir’s interaction model. I highly recommend it for anyone who is becoming a technical leader.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210120073302/http://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Project-DevOps-Helping-Business-ebook/dp/B00AZRBLHO/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=1450816934&amp;sr=1-1&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Phoenix Project by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, and George Spafford</a>. A modern version of <em>The Goal</em>, which helped reinforce past learnings about project management and software deployments.</p></li>
</ul>




<p>I hope 2015 treated you well! I look forward to a similarly stimulating 2016.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read January 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/books-read-january-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/books-read-january-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">Mistborn by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
A solid fantasty novel with an interesting magic system. In Mistborn, a
select few people are gifted with the ability to burn a metal internally
granting them abilities like improved strength or improved hearing. The
elevated ability lasts as long as the metal remains with the metal
burning in proportion to the power you demand of it. An even smaller
group can burn all metals. I liked it a lot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/art-of-conflict-management-achieving-solutions-for-life-work-and-beyond.html">The Art of Conflict Management by Michael
Dues</a>.
I now think that conflict management is the most important skill a
person can have. I wish this stuff was taught in school! It was very
helpful for me to learn the basics, which provided me with a framework
for understanding conflict (&ldquo;discomforting differences&rdquo;).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AFPVOTG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AFPVOTG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=JWTMJY6TXCVPZDCO">Finding Your Element by Sir Ken
Robinson</a>. Ken Robinson had a great
tech talk, so I thought I&rsquo;d like the book. It was good, but not really
what I need. I&rsquo;d recommend the book to young people who are floundering as they embark on
adulthood or middle-aged people struggling to understand where they fit
into the scheme of things.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C438CW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004C438CW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=7XHAOVDX33VKT7OV">No More Mr. Nice Guy by Robert
Glover</a>. I don&rsquo;t know how to feel about this book. I think it has a lot of really good information for nice guys who are unfulfilled; however, it raises some questions regarding masculinity and being kind but firm. Some of the positive points: men should spend time with other men, people should stand up for themselves and they should get what they want, and couples should evenly divide work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
