<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-15T18:39:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read January 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/books-read-january-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/books-read-january-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004H1TQBW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004H1TQBW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3QW5ERP7I3H66ZG6">Mistborn by Brandon Sanderson</a>.
A solid fantasty novel with an interesting magic system. In Mistborn, a
select few people are gifted with the ability to burn a metal internally
granting them abilities like improved strength or improved hearing. The
elevated ability lasts as long as the metal remains with the metal
burning in proportion to the power you demand of it. An even smaller
group can burn all metals. I liked it a lot.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/art-of-conflict-management-achieving-solutions-for-life-work-and-beyond.html">The Art of Conflict Management by Michael
Dues</a>.
I now think that conflict management is the most important skill a
person can have. I wish this stuff was taught in school! It was very
helpful for me to learn the basics, which provided me with a framework
for understanding conflict (&ldquo;discomforting differences&rdquo;).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AFPVOTG/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AFPVOTG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=JWTMJY6TXCVPZDCO">Finding Your Element by Sir Ken
Robinson</a>. Ken Robinson had a great
tech talk, so I thought I&rsquo;d like the book. It was good, but not really
what I need. I&rsquo;d recommend the book to young people who are floundering as they embark on
adulthood or middle-aged people struggling to understand where they fit
into the scheme of things.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004C438CW/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004C438CW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=7XHAOVDX33VKT7OV">No More Mr. Nice Guy by Robert
Glover</a>. I don&rsquo;t know how to feel about this book. I think it has a lot of really good information for nice guys who are unfulfilled; however, it raises some questions regarding masculinity and being kind but firm. Some of the positive points: men should spend time with other men, people should stand up for themselves and they should get what they want, and couples should evenly divide work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read December 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/books-read-december-2014/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/books-read-december-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a busy month for reading. Lots of good stuff!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00ARSJNW6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00ARSJNW6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KQP7U6OB4WMDL2XX">Dracula Chronicles: Son of the Dragon by Victor
Foia</a>. An interesting retelling of the life of Dracula. This book, the first of three, tracks Dracula in his teenage years as he makes his first kill. The book was really good, but I was looking for more fantasy.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00APA1NK6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00APA1NK6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=WMOFDYAVZR4UFKHT">Spellbound by Larry
Correia</a>. Correia has the fantasy adventure
story down. Very entertaining. I look forward to finishing the series
(Grimnoir Chronicles) soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CD360ZQ/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00CD360ZQ&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KKUCVAWJ3O2JOMPV">Alas, Babylon by Pat
Frank</a>. A slice of life in the alternate reality
where the cold war ended with nuclear war. I could see this
book as the precursor to The Road by McCarthy. I liked it.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00D4CBA50/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00D4CBA50&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=KN3MMS2ERWTKFAU7">At the Mountains of Madness by H.P.
Lovecraft</a>. Beware the elder
things buried in Antarctica.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00COOFBA4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00COOFBA4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=U74HXIB7CQ3OEZNU">How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big by Scott
Adams</a>. Scott Adams is the creator of the workplace comic, <a href="http://www.dilbert.com/">Dilbert</a>. In this book Adams lays out his lessons on life. Some of the high points: eat well, exercise, get into a routine, optimize your personal energy, learn as many different skills as you can (because success is likely to come from some combination of your skills), and passion is just a fancy way for successful people to say they got lucky. I really liked the book; I thought it was funny and informative, and I loved the humility with which the story was told. Where many books and life stories rewrite history and show how one success begot another, Adams instead talks about how his failures lead to success. The anecdotes were modest and on-point, which I found refreshing and brave.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009U9S6FI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009U9S6FI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=3S6RUEUONCG3UEAU">Man&rsquo;s Search for Meaning by Viktor
Frankl</a>. A Jewish psychiatrist&rsquo;s
Holocaust story helps explain his world view and motivate his
psychotherapy approach,
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logotherapy">Logotherapy</a>. I appreciated
that the book was honest without dwelling too much on the atrocities:
rather than recounting every terrible thing that happened, Frankl picks
a few key events that provide a broad understanding. Remarkably, Frankl
does something constructive with his grief. In the book he mentions that
Logotherapy might ask a patient why that patient does not commit
suicide because the answer reveals your meaning, which you can then work
with to heal. One of the most disturbing parts of the book for me was
Frankl&rsquo;s account of returning home to a nation that ignored the
concentration camps or downplayed their significance; he writes that for
many survivors life after the camp was harder than life in the camp.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009AYWPCI/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009AYWPCI&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=XSJDV3OEBODUC5IH">Futures and Frosting by Tara
Sivec</a>. Futures and Frosting tells the
story of how a single-mother is reunited with the father of her child;
after a lot of confusion, the couple gets married and has another kid,
then lives happily ever after. Without the humor, it would read like
an angsty young adult love story.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596518382/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0596518382&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=HYDQVVVHWRDD54ZB">Apprenticeship Patterns by Dave Hoover and Ade
Oshineye</a>.
This was probably the most accessible technical book I&rsquo;ve read. The
application of pattern language to a career is really clever and worked
well. As with software patterns, it&rsquo;s nice to see the path.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read November 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/books-read-november-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/books-read-november-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591845327/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1591845327&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=CRLWDIV34KA7TYF3">Leaders Eat Last by Simon
Sinek</a>. I loved this book because it
resonated with my hopes for the future of business. Sinek also brought
in some of my favorite psychological ideas in a way that I found
inspiring&ndash;I&rsquo;ve read a lot of the same research and come across the same
ideas, but I had not synthesized the data into a coherent worldview.
I&rsquo;d boil it down to the following: short-term profit maximization is
proving unsustainable even harmful for society; instead, you should treat
employees as people to enjoy sustained growth.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FC10MU/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000FC10MU&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=GQKSUWEFX3EOXXTL">American Gods by Neil
Gaiman</a>. Based on numerous positive reviews I
was really excited to read this book; unfortunately, I didn&rsquo;t care much
for it. In the preface Gaiman says that the book is long and meandering,
and he hit the nail on the head. I thought the main plot was pretty
interesting, but the tangents did not add anything for me. At times it
felt like I was reading a book for English class because I just didn&rsquo;t
understand the message.</p>

<p><a href="ttp://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00FCQQCX6/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00FCQQCX6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=ZEIIG5IJ2ZYDFWFL">The Emperor&rsquo;s Blades by Brian
Stavely</a>. I liked the book, but I&rsquo;m not
sure I&rsquo;m ready for another series just yet.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Poor-Economics-rethinking-poverty-ways-ebook/dp/B007CI81IQ/ref=sr_1_1?tag=theven01-20">Poor Economics by Abhijit Banerjee and Esther Duflo</a>. An accessible summary
of research about poor people worldwide. I loved the realistic approach
to helping people. Some of my favorite tidbits were that people donated
significantly more money when the message focused on a single,
identifiable person and that when given money, poor people tend to buy
more interesting food rather than more of the same (in the studies
people still ate around 1200 calories but they would incorporated more
meat and indulgences like tea rather than eating another 500 calories of
rice).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/language-a-to-z.html">Language A to Z by John
McWhorter</a>. Great course by the Great
Courses.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thegreatcourses.com/courses/customs-of-the-world-using-cultural-intelligence-to-adapt-wherever-you-are.html">Customs of the World by David
Livermore</a>. Good course by the Great
Courses.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read October 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/books-read-october-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/books-read-october-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000OI0G1Q/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000OI0G1Q&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=GO6FQAOF57SDDYD4">The Road by Cormac
McCarthy</a>. A short but powerful book&ndash;I see why it was made into a movie. Turns out the apocalypse is no fun.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005IHWBSY/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B005IHWBSY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=27ID6XF3TZLBRUHR">God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater by Kurt
Vonnegut</a>. I&rsquo;m ashamed to admit that this is my first Vonnegut book. I&rsquo;ve broken the seal, and I enjoyed it. The book has a socialist bent, so I&rsquo;d love to hear what a strong capitalist thought of this book.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006LSZECO/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B006LSZECO&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=CTUBO5ECTNQJQN3S">Gone Girl by Gillian
Flynn</a>. I finished this before seeing the movie. My overall reaction is, &ldquo;wow.&rdquo; I didn&rsquo;t like it, then liked it, then loved it, then didn&rsquo;t like it. It was original and well written, for what that&rsquo;s worth.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0787960756/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0787960756&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20">The Five Dysfunctions of a Team by Patrick
Lencioni</a>.
I&rsquo;ve now read a few Lencioni books, and I really enjoy them. I find his novel
approach to business lessons is very accessible. This book says you need
to first establish trust so that people will speak freely. Without
trust, people cannot engage in productive arguments, so people do not
buy in&ndash;they just quit arguing. Once you have trust, an open exchange of
ideas, and commitment to a shared vision, you can start holding people
accountable. Finally, you can focus on results. The five dysfunctions
are presented as a pyramid, which highlights the need to achieve the
previous level before moving up&ndash;I thought that was kind of like
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow's_hierarchy_of_needs">Maslow&rsquo;s Hierarchy of
Needs</a> applied
to business.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read September 2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/books-read-september-2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/books-read-september-2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a lot of series started now, and I&rsquo;m not sure which one I will continue next.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004KABDMA/ref=as_li_tl?tag=theven01-20">Satanic Verses by Salman Rushdie</a>. This book is really well written and historically important&ndash;the amount of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Satanic_Verses#Controversy">controversy</a> around this novel is unreal! Unfortunately, I did not care for the book. I made it through about 2/3 before I decided I&rsquo;d much rather be reading something else. Fear not! I&rsquo;ve read the summary so I know how it ends ;-)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005GLS7SU/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B005GLS7SU&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=DWGB7CV6GVSL3XT7">The Legend of Drizzt: The Collected Stories by R.A.
Salvatore</a>. I always like Drizzt stories. This is a sequence of vignettes that is less interesting than a complete story. It fills some gaps, but also spoils entire books; I&rsquo;d say you should read it after you&rsquo;ve read all the other books.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004J4WN0I/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004J4WN0I&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=ALNRNFQYLDFTUFJ3">Hounded: The Iron Druid Chronicles, Book One by Kevin
Hearne</a>. I found this very entertaining; I found it to be an interesting, fresh take on Druidic magic.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000WH7PLS/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000WH7PLS&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=FUZ7WVMF7CLGK3WU">Storm Front (The Dresden Files, Book 1) by Jim
Butcher</a>. A couple years ago I tore through the Dresden Files series on Netflix, so this reading was a long time coming. Unsurprisingly, the book is better than the show, but I&rsquo;d recommend both.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005K0AYH4/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B005K0AYH4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=theven01-20&amp;linkId=4AQUFSLWMQYJDDLC">Crucial Conversations by Kerry
Patterson</a>. This is a very useful book that offers &ldquo;tools for talking when the stakes are high.&rdquo; Some of the biggest takeaways for me: focus on what <em>you</em> can do better and &lsquo;start with heart,&rsquo; that is, be honest and heartfelt without blaming. I plan to re-read again sometime.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
