<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: personal | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//"/>
  <updated>2018-01-10T08:58:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite reads in 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite reads from 2017.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">Reamde</a> by Neal Stephenson &ndash; I have enjoyed every Neal Stephenson book I&rsquo;ve read, and this is no exception. I&rsquo;ve played a lot of online games over the years, so this book hooked me by starting off with a computer virus spread in an online game. It develops nicely from there.</li>
<li><a href="">The Moon is a Harsh Mistress</a> by Robert Heinlein &ndash; Truly ahead of its time. This book felt modern with its space travel and artificial intelligence, but it was written in the 1950s!</li>
<li><a href="">Ancillary Justice</a> by Leckie &ndash; This book has won a ton of awards so it is not too surprising that it is good. It has some really interesting ideas with AI and consciousness.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Series</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds</a> by Drew Hayes &ndash; College kids with super powers. That&rsquo;s a hell of a mashup. I found the three published books very entertaining. The characters were interesting, the scenarios were realistic, and the magic system was well thought out and balanced (which is not easy to do with super powers).</li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">The Path To Power</a> and <a href="">Means of Ascent</a> by Robert Caro &ndash; These are the first two books in a long biography series about LBJ, one of America&rsquo;s most interesting presidents. Ryan Holiday recommended these and I see why. Amazing character and great writing make these books easy to read. It helped me feel better about today&rsquo;s political climate.</li>
<li><a href="">Ideal Team Player</a> by Lencioni &ndash; Lencioni has carved out a niche with his leadership fables&mdash;basically, business books wrapped in a narrative. I&rsquo;ve read most of his books now and they fit together really nicely. I want to be an ideal team player and this book gave me food for thought.</li>
<li><a href="">Anatomy of Peace</a> by The Arbinger Institute &ndash; Another business book wraped in a narrative. Peace is a great goal, so I was glad to learn more about how we can all overcome conflict and find peace.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Books Read in 2017]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2017/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//books-read-2017</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are the books I read in 2017 categorized as fiction or non-fiction. (The list is also available on <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2017/48474315">Goodreads</a>.)</p>

<p>The thumbs up/down rating is fast and loose&mdash;don&rsquo;t take it too seriously.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">Reamde</a> by Stephenson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Blood Mirror</a> by Weeks &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Moon is a Harsh Mistress</a> by Heinlein &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Ancillary Justice</a> by Leckie &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Slaughterhouse-Five</a> by Vonnegut &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Norse Mythology</a> by Gaiman &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Age of Myth</a> by Sullivan &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Arcanum Unbounded</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Shadows for Silence in the Forests of Hell</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Hope of Atlantis</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Eleventh Metal</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Snapshot</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Oathbringer</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians</a> by Sanderson &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Invisible Man</a> by Ellison &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Leviathan Wakes</a> by Corey &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds: Year 1</a> by Hayes &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds: Year 2</a> by Hayes &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Super Powereds: Year 3</a> by Hayes &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Alice&rsquo;s Adventuers in Wonderland</a> by Carroll &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Highwayman</a> by Johnson &ndash; &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">Good Omens</a> by Pratchett and Gaiman &ndash; &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">Never Deal with a Dragon</a> by Charrette &ndash; &#128078;</li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="">The Path To Power</a> by Caro &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Means of Ascent</a> by Caro &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">On Power</a> by Caro &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Story of Human Language</a> by McWhorter &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Ideal Team Player</a> by Lencioni &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Four Obsessions of an Extraordinary Executive</a> by Lencioni &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Anatomy of Peace</a> by The Arbinger Institute &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Swoly Bible</a> by Mazzetti &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">And Then I Thought I Was a Fish</a> by Welch &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Tao Te Ching</a> by Tzu &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">The Inevitable</a> by Kelly &ndash; &#128077;</li>
<li><a href="">Bad Science</a> by Goldacre &ndash; &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">Bringing Home the Darma</a> by Kornfield &ndash; &#128078;</li>
<li><a href="">The Book of Mastery</a> by Selig &ndash; &#128078;</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My favorite reads in 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//favorite-books-read-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below are my favorite reads from 2016.</p>

<h3>Fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1RX9aIm">Lord of All Things</a> by Andreas Eschbach &ndash; This book had a lot of new-to-me ideas and the sci-fi was integrated nicely into a story I enjoyed. One of the things that stands out is that tradeoffs exist with every choice.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2ixJgRY">Seveneves</a> by Neal Stephenson &ndash; Amazing concepts that my mind keeps turning over. I love Neal Stephenson and this is yet another mind-expanding novel from him. This book really hit him as Elon Musk started speaking more publicly about getting off Earth.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in6xFW">Stories of Your Life and Others</a> by Ted Chiang &ndash; I don&rsquo;t tend to read many short stories, but I&rsquo;m glad I read this collection. About half the stories were really good and still have me thinking.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Series</h4>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1YefYmk">Red Rising by Pierce Brown</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/1UHiSBW">Riyria Chronicles by Michael J. Sullivan</a></li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iWcyur">Lightbringer series by Brent Weeks</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Non-fiction</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/294eAPo">Them: Adventures with Extremists</a> by Jon Ronson &ndash; A great story in the midst of a very extreme 2016.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2hHFvrV">Surely You&rsquo;re Joking, Mr. Feynman!: Adventures of a Curious Character</a> by Richard Feynman &ndash; This is my new standard for an autobiography. Entertaining and interesting throughout, with great insights into this curious character. I particularly liked that he didn&rsquo;t want more money because it would allow him to afford mistress, which he knew would ruin his life.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2iUcmre">Home Game: An Accidental Guide to Fatherhood</a> by Michael Lewis &ndash; I would recommend this to any new father. It&rsquo;s short and funny with Michael Lewis plainly saying so many things I had thought. I&rsquo;ve used his question &ldquo;what percentage of the parenting does each parent do?&rdquo; several times now. He says that fathers do much less than mothers but there&rsquo;s a lot of social stigma to admitting that, which made me feel better.</li>
<li><a href="http://amzn.to/2in8Et5">When Things Fall Apart: Heart Advice for Difficult Times</a> by Pema Chodron &ndash; This book dovetailed nicely with my efforts to control my emotions. I read no more than one chapter at a time because it&rsquo;s heavy, introspective stuff. I was thrilled that I read this beeok when I saw Derek Sivers mention Pema Chodron in his <a href="http://nownownow.com/about">about now pages post</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>That&rsquo;s my not-so-short list of favorites from 2016. I hope 2017 will be filled with as many great stories.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SXSW 2016 in Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//sxsw-2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//sxsw-2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>SXSW 2016 was great! I&rsquo;m enjoying the conference more every year. I think last year&rsquo;s presentations were more thought-provoking, but there were several good talks this year too.</p>

<h2>Friday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP90088">Invisible Influence and Winning at SXSW 2016</a> &ndash; Contagious was <a href="http://sethholloway.com/favorite-books-read-2015/">one of my favorite books of 2015</a> so I was excited for his keynote. It was good. He played a clip from his appearance on <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2078690/">Brain Games</a> where the show manipulated people into waiting in line for nothing. That idea reminds me a lot of <a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/derek_sivers_how_to_start_a_movement">Derek Sivers talk on how to start a movement</a> (which is awesome).</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP93149">President Barack Obama Keynote Conversation</a> &ndash; Super cool that Obama was at South by. I really like the POTUS connecting with the people (as opposed to the standard, stuffy keep-the-voters-at-arm&rsquo;s length).</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP91541">Google Self-Driving Car Project</a> &ndash; So cool. Last year&rsquo;s Moon Shots presentation by Dr. Astro Teller left me all warm and fuzzy about Google X, and this talk did too. I loved seeing the computer representation next to the camera version. The future is now. (I can&rsquo;t wait for self-driving cars.)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Saturday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP46272">NativeScript: The Future of Mobile App Development</a> &ndash; Wanna write a single JavaScript program that can run on iOS, Android, and Windows phone? Then NativeScript is for you! It&rsquo;s a neat idea, and I think the fact that we keep seeing write-once-run-on-any-native-platform projects shows how valuable such a project would be.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP92018">The Future of Media Companies</a> &ndash; Hard to believe that a BuzzFeed speech would have a click-bait title, right?!</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP92035">Daring Greatly</a> &ndash; To summarize: breathe. I&rsquo;m being flippant. Brene Brown is amazing and her keynote was no exception. One of my favorites.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP91923">Unstoppable Trends that are Changing the World</a> &ndash; Max, the co-founder and CTO of PayPal, is staggeringly smart. The presentation was good. The Q&amp;A was great. In the time it took to read a question, Max could come up with a brilliant, self-assured response that was delivered with precision. He invoked the idea of a shrewd, genius VC.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP48870">The Linguistic Secrets Found in Billions of Emoji</a> &ndash; I thought I could buy some nerd-cred with my wife with this one. I don&rsquo;t use emoji like most people use emoji :&ndash;\</li>
</ul>


<h2>Monday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP51950">Comments Are Terrible: But They Don&rsquo;t Have to Be</a> &ndash; My favorite insight was that the architecture of comment sections can change behavior; for example, a three-column comment section containing <code>for</code>, <code>against</code>, and <code>questions</code> increased civility.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP58524">Bad Robot, Epic Digital, and Google Present Moon Shot. The story of the Google Lunar XPRIZE</a> &ndash; JJ Abrams introduced a series of shows chronicling a few teams going for the Google Lunar X prize. Great videos! I love how space is cool now.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_OE05413">Silent Room by Simon Heijdens</a> &ndash; Anechoic chamber. Whoa. I only got a minute inside but it was a really neat experience.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tuesday</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP52737">The New Battle Over Encryption and How to Survive It</a> &ndash; Moxie Marlinspike is amazing. I don&rsquo;t know how someone so humble and idealistic has gained the spotlight, but I&rsquo;m so glad he has. I&rsquo;d rather listen to him than the standard pundit any day.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP57527">Cracking the Code to Your Unlimited Epic Potential</a> &ndash; To summarize: breathe.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP90100">Why Happiness Is Hard and How to Make It Easier</a> &ndash; To summarize: breathe.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP46758">The Secrets of Machine Learning Revealed</a> &ndash; A great summary of machine learning. I really liked how Dr. Domingos distilled the information stating the five schools of ML and their goals.</li>
<li><a href="http://schedule.sxsw.com/2016/events/event_PP57474">Closing Remarks: Bruce Sterling</a> &ndash; A SXSW tradition. This year&rsquo;s message seemed to be, &ldquo;by this time next year, Trump will be president, but the U.S. will survive.&rdquo; Bruce is an engaging, entertaining speaker full of energy and ideas.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android vs iOS]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com//thoughts-on-android-and-ios/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com//thoughts-on-android-and-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I work on Android and iOS I&rsquo;m refining my opinions. Below are my current thoughts about the two ecosystems and underlying languages.</p>

<h2>Objective C vs Java</h2>

<p>Note: I haven&rsquo;t used Swift enough to fairly compare Swift to Objective C. The presence of Swift calls into question the future of Objective C; however, I think Swift eliminates a lot of my gripes with Objective C.</p>

<h3>Objective C wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>Apple docs are generally more pleasant than JavaDocs.</li>
<li>You can pass messages to <code>nil</code> without a <code>NullPointerException</code>.</li>
<li><code>nil</code> is <code>false</code>, which fits how I generally think about problems and saves some typing (<code>if (foo)</code> is not as explicit but explicit null checks are noisy and easily forgotten).</li>
<li>Method names can be more expressive: <code>stringWithCString:inputString encoding:inputEncoding</code> is more clear to me than <code>String(String inputString, String encoding)</code>, which, in practice, is often more like <code>String(String s, String e)</code>. As the signature expands the problem becomes more pronounced. Objective C essentially forces named arguments.</li>
<li>Drama surrounding Java&rsquo;s future under Oracle; for example, Android Dalvik is definitely not Java <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalvik_(software)#Licensing_and_patents"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalvik_">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalvik_</a>(software)#Licensing_and_patents</a></li>
</ul>


<h3>Java wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>In wide use outside mobile development, so Java is well known and understood</li>
<li>Simpler memory management, which decreases the amount of syntax and leads to fewer bugs. This combined with the fact that Java is more widely used means that people can more easily ramp up on Android.</li>
</ul>


<h2>iOS vs Android</h2>

<h3>Android wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>Easy and inexpensive (a one-time $25 fee) to create and publish apps.</li>
<li>Registering to open URLs. In Android an app can register to open specific links, like <code>https://youtube.com</code> or <code>seth://foo</code>. This improves the user experience by operating on the link in the best app: if you have the YouTube app, open the video in the app, otherwise fall back to the default browser. iOS achieves a similar effect but cannot register for <code>https://</code> schemes. In practice it works well enough, but custom schemes aren’t as ubiquitous as HTTP(S).</li>
<li>Strings and localization. Android forces you to use a message catalog, which has several advantages: (1) it’s better for reuse; (2) it makes it easier to refactor; (3) it centralizes text so docs and translators can engage more easily; (4) the toolchain is more stable&mdash;Xcode crashes a lot when working with localization and it doesn’t update text changes made through interface builder</li>
</ul>


<h3>iOS wins</h3>

<ul>
<li>One true way to do most things. iOS is pretty strict, but it&rsquo;s easier to find the proper way to do things and leads to greater consistency.</li>
<li>More stable platform.</li>
<li>Higher quality apps and community, on average. While Apple&rsquo;s approval process is a pain and their developer program fees are steep (compared to Android&rsquo;s $0 cost), this probably leads to higher quality.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
