<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: exercise | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/blog/categories/exercise/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-08T19:29:45-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supplements are unregulated and unproven]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/supplements-are-unregulated-and-unproven/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/supplements-are-unregulated-and-unproven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered how some people get so big? Rice flour!</p>

<object width="425" height="344" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/3mfQTiumsO4&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed width="425" height="344" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/3mfQTiumsO4&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" allowFullScreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /></object>


<p>From <a title="YouTube: Truth about Supplements" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3mfQTiumsO4" target="_blank">YouTube</a></p>

<p>The story makes an excellent point: supplements are not regulated and often hide behind a veil of proprietary secrecy. This is true for vitamins as well.</p>

<p><a title="Freakonomics - the obesity epidemic" href="http://www.freakonomics.com/2010/02/26/freakonomics-radio-fat-edition-is-the-obesity-epidemic-for-real/">Listen to this Freakonomics</a> podcast for a great segment about the politics of obesity where political science professor <a title="J Eric Oliver at University of Chicago" href="http://political-science.uchicago.edu/people/faculty/oliver.shtml">Eric Oliver</a> argues that a lot of people are making a lot of money by drumming up an obsession with fitness and weight. Follow the money!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixie: The Black Sheep of Bikes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/fixie-the-black-sheep-of-bikes/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/fixie-the-black-sheep-of-bikes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After I started riding my bike more often, I got interested in bike culture. I&rsquo;ve talked to seasoned UT cyclists learning best routes, safety tips, how to maintain a bike, how to stay warm/cool, etc. One of my favorite topics has been the fixie. The fixie, or <a title="Wikipedia: Fixed-gear Bicycle" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed-gear_bicycle" target="_blank">fixed-gear bicycle</a> is something of an anomaly. Fixies do not have &ldquo;speeds&rdquo; like the ubiquitous childhood 10-speed; instead, fixies are single-speed bikes that directly tie pedal rotations to tire rotations. If your tires are moving, so are your pedals. So much for coasting!  Most fixies do not have brakes&mdash;not even <a title="Wikipedia: Coaster Brakes" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bicycle_brake_systems#Coaster_brakes" target="_blank">coaster brakes</a> like your old BMX bike! A fixie rider has to stop the bike by resisting the pedals. By avoiding modern technology, fixies are the black sheep of bikes.</p>

<p>Below is a picture of a typical fixie. There are a few things to notice</p>

<ul>
<li>the lack of gears and a tight chain</li>
<li>the colored wheels</li>
<li>the thin, custom handlebars</li>
<li>somewhat flashy, although aesthetically pleasing</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.tonicfab.com/uploaded_images/blk_fixie_7-794097.jpg"><img title="A typical fixie" src="http://www.tonicfab.com/uploaded_images/blk_fixie_7-794097.jpg" alt="A typical fixie" width="400" height="346" /></a></p>

<p>Please see Wired&rsquo;s article on five <a title="Wired.com: 5 inexplicable fixie trends" href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2009/04/five-inexplicab/" target="_blank">inexplicable fixie trends</a> for more ways to identify a fixie.</p>

<p>Fixies seems to have risen to prominence in New York City where crazy bicycle messengers would deftly maneuver through traffic en route to deliveries. Other big cities followed suit and a cult of cool was spawned: if you didn&rsquo;t ride a fixie, you weren&rsquo;t hardcore.</p>

<p>Fixed-gear cycling is said to be the most intense experience one can have with the road, and the bicycle is incredibly easy to maintain because it is so simple. Opponents point out that this style of riding is hard on the body, particularly the knees, and generally dumb because 1) brakes are incredibly useful, especially in the city, and 2) gears are incredibly useful, especially in a hilly city where speed and effort need to be modulated quickly.</p>

<p>You see quite a few fixies in Austin, generally ridden by hipsters. I&rsquo;ll unscientifically say they&rsquo;re &frac14; bikes I see ridden (while the absolute number of fixed-gear bicycles is small, fixie riders use their bikes a lot so you see more of them as a percentage). Originally, I thought the fixed-gear bicycle was just a fad, but the ridership is still strong.</p>

<p>In case you&rsquo;re wondering why anyone would ever ride a fixie, here are a few videos that demonstrate the true power of fixies (hint: none of these videos take place on <a title="6street.com: Guadalupe" href="http://www.6street.com/6s_pg_guadalupe.htm" target="_blank">the drag</a>):</p>

<object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="425" height="344" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/76hg3ss7gQE&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/76hg3ss7gQE&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object>


<p>Or the more graceful, feminine bicycle ballerinas: <a title="YouTube: Bicycle Ballerinas" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48C_KHwt53c" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48C_KHwt53c">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48C_KHwt53c</a></a> and the bicycle ballerina: <a title="YouTube.com: Bicycle Ballerina" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxV1X5EzfCA" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxV1X5EzfCA">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxV1X5EzfCA</a></a></p>

<p>What do you think? Would you ride a fixie? Do you already? Are they a good-for-nothing trend or the ultimate bike experience? Perhaps both?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do simple minds lead to healthy bodies?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/do-simple-minds-lead-to-healthy-bodies/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/do-simple-minds-lead-to-healthy-bodies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do simple minds lead to healthy bodies? Animals are simpler than humans, and their physical abilities are incredible. In general, animals are lean and strong while humans are trending towards&hellip; well, not lean and strong :)</p>

<p>I make money using my brain, not my brawn. My thought-intensive labor pays well, and I use the pay for food&mdash;among other needs and wants. I don&rsquo;t use my body to obtain food, and I don&rsquo;t use my body to get paid; that means I have to consciously exercise this human machine. At the same time, food is easily accessible. Add to this reality the fact that <a title="Does thinking make us fat? Yep." href="http://abcnews.go.com/Technology/SmartHome/story?id=5763150&amp;page=1" target="_blank">thinking makes us fat</a> (because the act uses glucose which destabilizes insulin levels and makes us hungry).</p>

<p>On the other hand, dogs do not have to work nor hunt for food, yet they are fit. Dogs live to run around. You can throw the ball forever, and they will continue to go full tilt, retrieve, return, and repeat. Their simple minds think chasing a ball is the best thing ever, and they don&rsquo;t see it as exercise.</p>

<p>Children are the same way. No, I&rsquo;m not calling your child a dog. However, children are simpler than adults and gleefully play all day. To simpler kinds, exercise seems to come easily: it is not necessary, it is not a chore, it is fun. We should approach exercise as children do. Find something active that you like, and do it. It is play. It is unstructured. They simply have too much energy and want to get rid of it. How can we do the same?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are helmets worth it while cycling?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/are-helmets-worth-it-while-cycling/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/are-helmets-worth-it-while-cycling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After <a title="seth holloway dot com post" href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/?p=144" target="_blank">posting yesterday</a>, I explored the <a title="How We Drive Blog" href="http://www.howwedrive.com/" target="_blank">How We Drive Blog</a> more. There&rsquo;s a <a title="Helmets make you safer?" href="http://www.howwedrive.com/2008/10/01/to-wear-or-not-to-wear-and-is-that-even-the-right-question-ian-walker-on-cycle-helmets/" target="_blank">fascinating article</a> by a research scientist who tried to determine if wearing a helmet makes us safer. The short answer, no one knows.</p>

<p>To summarize, it may actually be better to <strong>not </strong>wear a helmet because people will be more aggressive around you if you are wearing a helmet. Cyclists are also riskier because of a perceived increase in safety. (Psychological research says that monotony and repetition lull us into feeling safe; apply that to cyclists who do everything &ldquo;right&rdquo; and have never been in an accident.) Additionally, most cyclists die with head and chest injuries; no helmet can help your crushed torso.</p>

<p>Arguing for helmet, they will help with slow speed crashes and self-induced falls.</p>

<p>I got a chuckle from this bit: <em>A bicyclist visited their doctor with a damaged knee following a crash. “You should have been wearing a helmet,” says the doctor sternly. “How would that have saved my knee?” replies the cyclist.</em></p>

<p>So, does wearing a helmet make you safer? Hard to say!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weather becomes more important when you ride your bike]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/weather-becomes-more-important-when-you-ride-your-bike/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.sethholloway.com/sethholloway/weather-becomes-more-important-when-you-ride-your-bike</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started riding my bike to campus this summer (started around May 2008). In the few months since then I have learned to pay more attention to the weather and my departure time. Beyond clear skies and moderate temperatures I treasure fewer cars on the road, adequate ambient light, and green traffic signals!</p>

<p>I saved the best for last: I want low humidity! This morning Austin is around 90% humidity and the ride into campus was miserable&mdash;despite moderate temperatures. With high humidity the body cannot cool off properly and it feels like you&rsquo;re pedaling through a swimming pool.</p>

<p>And since I&rsquo;m talking about weather, I&rsquo;d like to share a couple cool sites I found recently. <a title="umbrellatoday.com" href="http://umbrellatoday.com/" target="_blank">Umbrellatoday</a> simplifies the weather interface and simply tells you whether or not you need an umbrella. Contrast that to the <a title="weather.com" href="http://www.weather.com/outlook/health/allergies/local/78757?lswe=78757&amp;lwsa=Weather36HourAllergiesCommand&amp;from=searchbox" target="_blank">weather.com page</a>; I see graphics, radar images, a lot of text, multiple different colors, and several days worth of forecasts. I just need to know if it will rain today so I can make an informed choice about riding my bike versus taking the bus, and Umbrellatoday comes to my rescue.</p>

<p>Another site that keeps it simple is <a title="Stormpulse.com" href="http://www.stormpulse.com/" target="_blank">Stormpulse</a>, an excellent source for tropical storm information. Contrast the Stormpulse interface to the <a title="Stormtracker on NOAA" href="http://www.stormtracker.noaa.gov/" target="_blank">official government storm tracking website</a>. There are times when I want to find out about weather events without wading through all the other stuff (think <a title="cnn.com" href="http://wwww.cnn.com/" target="_blank">cnn.com</a>); Stormpulse is perfect in those situations.</p>

<p>Note: both sites are still new to me (and the world in general, I think). We&rsquo;ll see how accurate and reliable they are. As always, your mileage may vary.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
