<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: exercise | Seth Holloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/blog/categories/exercise/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sethholloway.com/"/>
  <updated>2021-08-15T14:01:51-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://sethholloway.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Holloway]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Supplements are unregulated and unproven]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/supplements-are-unregulated-and-unproven/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/supplements-are-unregulated-and-unproven</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered how some people get so big? Rice flour!</p>

<object width="425" height="344" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/3mfQTiumsO4&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed width="425" height="344" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/3mfQTiumsO4&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1" allowFullScreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /></object>


<p>From <a title="YouTube: Truth about Supplements" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3mfQTiumsO4" target="_blank">YouTube</a></p>

<p>The story makes an excellent point: supplements are not regulated and often hide behind a veil of proprietary secrecy. This is true for vitamins as well.</p>

<p><a title="Freakonomics - the obesity epidemic" href="http://www.freakonomics.com/2010/02/26/freakonomics-radio-fat-edition-is-the-obesity-epidemic-for-real/">Listen to this Freakonomics</a> podcast for a great segment about the politics of obesity where political science professor <a title="J Eric Oliver at University of Chicago" href="http://political-science.uchicago.edu/people/faculty/oliver.shtml">Eric Oliver</a> argues that a lot of people are making a lot of money by drumming up an obsession with fitness and weight. Follow the money!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixie: The Black Sheep of Bikes]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/fixie-the-black-sheep-of-bikes/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/fixie-the-black-sheep-of-bikes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After I started riding my bike more often, I got interested in bike culture. I&rsquo;ve talked to seasoned UT cyclists learning best routes, safety tips, how to maintain a bike, how to stay warm/cool, etc. One of my favorite topics has been the fixie. The fixie, or <a title="Wikipedia: Fixed-gear Bicycle" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fixed-gear_bicycle" target="_blank">fixed-gear bicycle</a> is something of an anomaly. Fixies do not have &ldquo;speeds&rdquo; like the ubiquitous childhood 10-speed; instead, fixies are single-speed bikes that directly tie pedal rotations to tire rotations. If your tires are moving, so are your pedals. So much for coasting!  Most fixies do not have brakes&ndash;not even <a title="Wikipedia: Coaster Brakes" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bicycle_brake_systems#Coaster_brakes" target="_blank">coaster brakes</a> like your old BMX bike! A fixie rider has to stop the bike by resisting the pedals. By avoiding modern technology, fixies are the black sheep of bikes.</p>

<p>Below is a picture of a typical fixie. There are a few things to notice</p>

<ul>
<li>the lack of gears and a tight chain</li>
<li>the colored wheels</li>
<li>the thin, custom handlebars</li>
<li>somewhat flashy, although aesthetically pleasing</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.tonicfab.com/uploaded_images/blk_fixie_7-794097.jpg"><img title="A typical fixie" src="http://www.tonicfab.com/uploaded_images/blk_fixie_7-794097.jpg" alt="A typical fixie" width="400" height="346" /></a></p>

<p>Please see Wired&rsquo;s article on five <a title="Wired.com: 5 inexplicable fixie trends" href="http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2009/04/five-inexplicab/" target="_blank">inexplicable fixie trends</a> for more ways to identify a fixie.</p>

<p>Fixies seems to have risen to prominence in New York City where crazy bicycle messengers would deftly maneuver through traffic en route to deliveries. Other big cities followed suit and a cult of cool was spawned: if you didn&rsquo;t ride a fixie, you weren&rsquo;t hardcore.</p>

<p>Fixed-gear cycling is said to be the most intense experience one can have with the road, and the bicycle is incredibly easy to maintain because it is so simple. Opponents point out that this style of riding is hard on the body, particularly the knees, and generally dumb because 1) brakes are incredibly useful, especially in the city, and 2) gears are incredibly useful, especially in a hilly city where speed and effort need to be modulated quickly.</p>

<p>You see quite a few fixies in Austin, generally ridden by hipsters. I&rsquo;ll unscientifically say they&rsquo;re &frac14; bikes I see ridden (while the absolute number of fixed-gear bicycles is small, fixie riders use their bikes a lot so you see more of them as a percentage). Originally, I thought the fixed-gear bicycle was just a fad, but the ridership is still strong.</p>

<p>In case you&rsquo;re wondering why anyone would ever ride a fixie, here are a few videos that demonstrate the true power of fixies (hint: none of these videos take place on <a title="6street.com: Guadalupe" href="http://www.6street.com/6s_pg_guadalupe.htm" target="_blank">the drag</a>):</p>

<object classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" width="425" height="344" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="src" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/76hg3ss7gQE&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><embed type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="425" height="344" src="http://www.youtube.com/v/76hg3ss7gQE&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1&amp;" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true"></embed></object>


<p>Or the more graceful, feminine bicycle ballerinas: <a title="YouTube: Bicycle Ballerinas" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48C_KHwt53c" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48C_KHwt53c">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=48C_KHwt53c</a></a> and the bicycle ballerina: <a title="YouTube.com: Bicycle Ballerina" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxV1X5EzfCA" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxV1X5EzfCA">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxV1X5EzfCA</a></a></p>

<p>What do you think? Would you ride a fixie? Do you already? Are they a good-for-nothing trend or the ultimate bike experience? Perhaps both?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Riding your bike to campus]]></title>
    <link href="http://sethholloway.com/riding-your-bike-to-campus/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sethholloway.com/riding-your-bike-to-campus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>April 17, 2008 is the day that the world will remember something great: Seth Holloway&rsquo;s first bike ride to campus. Despite living further from campus than ever before (and that&rsquo;s saying something since I&rsquo;ve been here for 7 years), I took the plunge and rode my bike today.</p>

<p>The five miles took thirty minutes in traffic. I arrived on campus fully awake and sweaty; a combination I had never experienced so early before. My only gripe was a Volvo-driving soccer mom who hugged the curb and kept me from riding up to the stoplight along the curb. All the other drivers were courteous and kind to this noob-biker.</p>

<p>As I get more fit, tune my bike better, and hit lights at the right time I think I could shave off five minutes pretty easily.  Here&rsquo;s to Austin weather staying pleasant enough for bike riding for weeks to come!</p>

<p>Thanks to Mike for excellent advice on the route and helping me to get comfortable riding my bike. Additional thanks to Tony and Dave for helping to acclimate me with the nuances of riding a bike to campus.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
